5,6,7,8
5,6,7,8
Anybody seen the Kelly Sisters?
有谁看到凯莉姐妹?
You, you're up in five
你,五分钟後换你上场
- Keep the change, Charlie - Thanks
零钱不用找了,查理 谢谢
Where the hell have you been?
你到底跑哪去了?
- And where is Veronica? - She's onto herself tonight.
薇若妮卡人呢? 她今晚要自己过来
But they paid to see your sister act
但观众花钱是来看你妹妹表演的
Don't sweat it, I can do it alone
别紧张,我一个人也行
Shit!
该死!
Come on, move it, move it Hurry up
快点,动呀动! 快!
Tell them you're here
告诉他们你到了
Ladies and gentlemen
各位先生女士
The Onyx Club is proud to present Chicago's hottest dancing duo
现在向你们隆重介绍芝加哥 最火辣的舞蹈二人组
Two jazz babes moving as one
两位爵士辣妹共同演出
The Kelly Sisters
凯莉姐妹花
Come on babe Why don't we paint the town
快点,辣妹,我们何不痛痛快快地玩
In all that Jazz I'm gonna rouge my knees
纵情爵士之中,我要在膝盖涂上口红
and roll my stockings down
卷下长袜
And all that jazz Start the car
纵情爵士、驾车驰骋
I know a whoopee spot
我知道一个狂欢好去处
where the gin is cold
那儿琴酒冰凉透顶
but the piano's hot
琴声悠扬
It's just a noisy hall where there's a nightly brawl
整夜喧嚣不已的嘈杂大厅
And all...
并纵...
...that...
...情...
Jazz
...爵士
Skidoo
来吧!
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士
Hotcha!
热舞吧!
Whoopee!
狂欢吧!
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士
Slick you hair Wear your buckle shoes
梳理好发型,穿上有扣环的鞋子
I hear the father dip
我听见那酒仙
Is gonna blow the blues
吹奏一曲蓝调
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士
Hold on, hon We're gonna bunny hug
等等,宝贝,我们相拥而跳
I bought some aspirin
我买了阿司匹灵
Down at United Drug
在连锁药局
In case you shake apart
以防万一你摇散了
And wanna a brand new start
再重来一遍
to do
跳上
that
一曲
Jazz
爵士
Let's go baby
我们走吧,宝贝
But I didn't even meet your friend
但我甚至还没跟你朋友见面
That, that manager guy
那位经理啊
Don't worry, Roxy
别担心,萝西
It's all taken care of
全都处理好了
You told him about me
你跟他谈过我了?
Yeah, kid It's all arranged
是的,全安排妥当了
Find a flask We're playing fast and loose
找个瓶子,我们来玩松紧游戏
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士
Right up here is where I store the juice
将果汁倒进去
Come on babe We're gonna brush the sky
来吧,宝贝,我们来彩绘夜空
I bet you lucky Lindy
我敢说你那幸运林迪
Never flew so high
从未飞过这么高
'Cause in the stratosphere
因为高空之上
How could he lend an ear
他怎有暇去倾听
To all...
那...
...that...
...爵士的...
Jazz
...风情
Oh, you're gonna see her sheba shimmy shake
哦,你会看见她的示巴女王摇啊摇
And All That Jazz!
并纵情爵士!
Oh, she's gonna shimmy till her garters break
哦,她要摇到袜带都断掉
And All That Jazz
并纵情爵士
Show her where to park her girdle
教她腰带该怎么系
Oh, her mother's blood is curdle
哦,她母亲的血都会凝固
If she'd hear
要是她听到
Her baby's queer
她孩子如此著迷
For All That Jazz!
那爵士风情!
Oh, Mrs. Brucewits Mrs. Hart
哦,布鲁斯威兹太太 哈特太太
This is Fred
这位是佛瑞德
He's my brother
他是我哥哥
All that Jazz
纵情爵士
Come on babe, why don't we paint the town?
快点,辣妹,我们何不痛痛快快地玩
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士之中
I'm gonna rouge my knees
我要在膝盖涂上口红
and roll my stockings down
卷下长袜
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士
Start the car
驾车驰骋
I know a whoopee spot
我知道一个狂欢好去处
Where martini is cold
那儿琴酒冰凉透顶
But the piano's hot
琴声悠扬
It's just a noisy hall
嘈杂大厅里
Where there's a nightly brawl
整夜喧嚣不已
And all that Jazz
洋溢著爵士音符
Say it again, Fred
再说一遍,佛瑞德
Ah, you're the star, kid
啊,你是个明星,乖乖
My little shooting star
我的小明星
No, I'm no one's wife
哦,我非为人妻
But, oh, I love my life
但我热爱我生命
And All That Jazz!
和爵士风情!
That Jazz
爵士风情
Oh, say it again, Fred
哦,再说一遍,佛瑞德
Jesus
天啊!
Where is the fire?
干嘛急著要走?
Amos ain't home till midnight
艾默斯要到午夜才回家
Freddie
佛瑞迪
Fred
佛瑞德
Hey, ...you know
嘿...你知道
I don't want you to feel I'm nagging at you or anything
我不想让你觉得我太唠叨
But don't think it's about time that I met your friend out of the Onyx
可你不觉得该是时候 把我介绍给你那些朋友了吗?
I mean it's been a month since you told him about me
我是说你说提过也已经过了一个月了
I know
我知道
Cause that was a night Velma Kelly plugged her husband and her sister
因为那晚薇玛凯莉射杀她老公和她老妹
You really say that she found when they kissed together
你说她真的看到他们两个在一起接吻?
Gosh if I found Amos soping it into somebody else
天啊!要是我看到艾默斯跟别人这样
Bing bing gone with the wind, right
就给他砰砰,对吗?
It's getting late
太晚了
I have been thinking a lot about mattress
我一直在考虑买什么床垫
I never get a really good idea I write it down in my diary before it goes out of my head
我记性不好,趁没忘掉前写在日记里头
And it occured to me the other day
等哪一天我突然想到
That all the really, really knocked out acts
真的付诸行动买下来
Have, you know, something little different going on you know
你知道吗? 事情就会有所不同了
Like eh...our signature bed
彷佛...这张床注定是我们的
And I thought, I thought that nothing
而且我认为,我认为...天下没有...
Could be a loof
白吃的午餐
You know
你知道吗?
Give them just enough to get them good in hungry you know
将他们喂饱了
Always leave them one more
只会让他们更加食髓知味
Hey, once I get a name for myself
嘿,等我想好要取什么名字时
Maybe, maybe we could open up a club in Varum, you know
也许我们可以在瓦伦开间俱乐部
You could run it
你负责经营
and I could be the headliner
我负责　　表演
What's the idea?
你觉得不好吗?
Wake up, kid, you're never gonna have an act
醒醒吧,你永远不可能演出的
Says who?
谁说的?
Face it, Roxie
面对现实吧,萝西
You're too bit talent with skinny legs
你两腿修长,很有天赋
but I'm just a furniture salesman
不过我只是个家俱销售员
Dear but you got connections, you know
亲爱的,但你有人脉啊,你知道的
The guy down the club
俱乐部的那个人啊
There is no guy
根本就没这个人
Yet, that night
可是..那晚
It was the first night I set foot in that joint
那是我头一次涉足那个场所
I was collecting out a bed for the trumbone player
我是给那个吹喇叭的送床去的
So you never told anyone about me?
那么说你根本没和谁提起过我?
Sugar, you are hot stuff
蜜糖,你这么正点
I would say anything to get a piece of that
为了能和你上床,我什么都敢说
And now, now?
那现在呢,现在呢?
We've had some laughs Let's just leave it with that
既然爽过了,就到此为止吧
Fred
佛瑞德
You can't do this to me
你不能这么对我
You get off!
给我滚开!
You touch me again, I'll put your lights out
你敢再碰我一下,就让你好看
Wait
等等
Your husband will be home, so why don't you watch yourself
你丈夫马上回来了 你何不先整理一下自己丁容
We ain't gonna hit no sheets again
我们再也不会在一块了
You're a liar, Fred
你是个骗子,佛瑞德
Oh yes, so what?
哦,是啊,那又怎么样?
You lied to me
你骗了我
- You lied to me - That's right, sweetheart, that's right
没错,甜心,没错
You're son of a bitch
你真是王八蛋!
Hotcha
热力
Whoopee
欢欣
Why you're bothering, Sal
你费那个劲干嘛,沙尔
This one's all wrapped up
这都裹起来了
I hear it's a new city record
我听说这是个本城的新纪录
from killing to confession in an hour for that
从杀人到认罪才一个小时
Where did you get the murder weapon?
你的杀人凶器是哪里来的?
I keep a gun in the underwear drawer
我放内衣的抽屉里藏了把枪
Just in case of trouble, you know
只是以防不备,你懂吧?!
That's just fine, sign right there, Mr. Hart
很好,请在这里签字,哈特先生
Freely and gladly
很乐意遵命
And mind that you don't say we beat you up when you get upon the witness stand
提醒你上了证人席时 可别说是我们将你屈打成招
No I gave myself up, surrendered at my own freewill
不,我是自愿自首的
Isn't he the cheerful murderer?
他就是那个可恶的杀人凶手吗?
Shooting a burgalar ain't murder
打死个小偷不算谋杀
Just last week the jury sancted a man
上周陪审团才刚释放了一个人
I'm always greatful for citizens the law
我一向很感谢市民对法律的关心
Get in there
进去
You too
还有你
Sit down
坐下
OK, from the top
好吧,从头讲起
A man's got a right to protect his home and his loved ones, right?
男人有权保护他的家和他爱的人,对吗?
Of course he has
当然有
Well I come home from the garage, I see him climbing through the window
我从修车厂回家,看见他正从窗口爬进去
Aha?
是吗?
With my wife Roxie in there sleeping like an angel
我妻子萝西在房里睡得像个天使
Is that true, Mrs. Hart?
是真的吗,哈特太太?
I'm telling you My wife has nothing to do with it
我说了这和我老婆一点关系也没有
She wouldn't hurt a worm Not even a worm
她连一支小虫都不忍伤害
Was until I fire the first shot She won't even open her eyes
若非我开了第一枪,她也不会睁开眼睛
She sleeping
她睡得很沉
I would say she could sleep to the saint patty's day parade
我敢说就算外面在游行,她照样睡得著
When I think what would happen if I went out for a beer with the guys
我在想如果我和别人出去喝酒了
instead of coming straight home
没有直接回家的话,不知会发生什么事呢
It makes you sick when you think about it
光想想都让人害怕
For her first number, Ms. Roxie Hart would like to sing a song of love and devotion
萝西哈特太太头一首要唱的是 关於爱情和奉献的歌
Dedicated to her dear husband Amos
献给她亲爱的丈夫艾默斯
Sometimes I'm right
有时是我对
Sometimes I'm wrong
有时是我错
But he doesn't care
但他从不在乎
He'll string along
依然陪著我
He loves me so
他爱我那样深
That funny honey of mine!
我那有趣的爱人!
Sometimes I'm down
有时我心情低落
Sometimes I'm up
有时我心情愉快
But he follows 'round
但他依然紧紧跟随
Like some droopy-eyed pup
像只哈巴狗一样
He loves me so
他爱我那样深
That funny honey of mine!
我那有趣的爱人!
Like I said
就像我说的
Even after I shot him,  he kept coming at me
我开枪打了他之後,他还是继续冲过来
So I had to pull the trigger again
所以我只好再扣下扳机
He ain't no sheik
他不会捻花惹草
That's no great physique
也没有粗壮的体格
And Lord knows he ain't got the smarts
天知道他资质不够聪颖
But look at that soul
可是看看他的灵
I tell you, that whole
告诉你们,他整个灵
Is a whole lot greater
可是比他身上所有部位
Than the sum of his parts
加起来还要大
And if you knew him like me
如果你们晓得他喜欢我
I know you'd agree
我知道你们会同意这点的
What if the world
万一世人...
Slander my name?
诽谤我的名声
Why, he'd be right there
他会挺身而出
Taking the blame
承担世人的辱骂
He loves me so
他爱我那样深
And it all suits me fine
无微不至呵护著我
That funny, sunny, honey
我那有趣的、笑容灿烂的、甜蜜的
Hubby of mine!
...老公
I mean supposin', just supposin'
我意思是假设一下,只是假设
He'd violated her or something
他说不定会侵犯她或什么的
- You know what I mean? Violated - I know what you mean
你明白我的意思吗? 侵犯 我明白你的意思
Or something, think how terrible that would've been
或者怎么样,想想那会多么可怕
It's a good thing I got home from work on time
幸亏我下班後及时赶回家
I'm tellin' you that
我告诉你
I say I' m telling you that
事情经过就是那样
Name of deceased...Fred Casely
死者是佛瑞德凯斯利
Fred Casely?
佛瑞德凯斯利?
How could he be a burglar? My wife knows him!
他怎么会是小偷? 我太太认识他!
He sold us our furniture!
他卖家俱给我们呢
He gave us ten percent off
还给我们打了九折
Lord knows he ain't got the smarts
天知道他资质不够聪颖
She told me he was a burglar.
她告诉我说他是个小偷
You mean he was dead when you got home?
你是说你回家时,他就已经死了?
She had him covered with a sheet
她用床单盖住他
and she's tellin' me some cock and bull story about this burglar
然後编了一篇关於这小偷的事
and I ought to say I did it 'cause I was sure to get off
说我应该背黑锅 因为我肯定不会被判有罪
"Help me, Amos" she says it's my god damn hour of needs
她说:「救救我,艾默斯! 现在是我最　要你帮助的时候」
Now, he shot off his trap
如今他说穿诡计
I can't stand that sap
我受不了那蠢材!
(Amos) And I believed her! (Roxie) Look at him go
不过我相信她 看著他离去
(Amos) That cheap little tramp. (Roxie) Rattin' on me
那家伙是个无赖 出卖了我
(Amos) So she was two-timing me, huh? (Roxie) With just one more brain
所以她骗了我是吗? 才稍微聪明点就想去哪里?!
(Amos) Boy, I'm down at the garage, working my butt off fourteen hours a day (Roxie) If they string me up
小子,我在修车厂一天工作14个小时 如果他们判绞刑处死我
And she's up there munchin' on bon-bons
而她却舒舒服服地...
And trampling around like a goddamn fruisy
像个该死的妓女到处勾三引四
She thought she could
她以为打好如意算盘
I wasn't born yet
我可不是三岁小孩
I tell you there's something a man just can't take
告诉你任何男人也无法忍受戴绿帽
And this time she pushed me too far
这回她逼人太甚了
That little chiseler
那小骗子
Boy, what a sap I was
小子,我真是太蠢了
You double-crosser, you big blover  mouth! You promised you'd say...
你这叛徒、超级大嘴巴! 你答应过你会说...
What're you talking about, you've been tricking me, Roxanne
你在说什么呀?! 你一直骗的我团团转,萝西
You told me he was a burglar
你骗我说他是小偷
The whole time you're been jazzling
结果整段时间你们在胡搞
You are a disloyal husband
你是个不忠诚的老公
Look, it's true I shot him. But...
听著,是真的! 我开枪打他,不过...
It was out of defense He was trying to burgle me
是出於自卫,他想偷我东西
And what I hear is he's been burgling you three times a week for the last month
我所听到的是最近一个月 他每个礼拜偷你三次
So what do you say, Mrs?
你说呢,夫人?
- That's him alright - Thank you
是他没错 谢谢
Your story doesn' wash, Mrs Hart
你的鬼话骗不了人,哈特太太
So try this emphasize
我再重申一次
Fred Caseley was a good time on the side with goofy here's a milk ticket
佛瑞德凯斯利在这边跟个傻女孩寻欢 这里有张餐券
Milk ticket? He could buy my liquor
餐券? 他可以请我喝酒啊
And Fred Casely could
佛瑞德凯斯利可能...
With a wife and  5 little Caseleys Or did he forget to mention them?
有一个老婆和五个小孩 还是他忘了提到这点?
What?
什么?
All his
都是他的
That bastard
那个混蛋!
Yeah, I killed him, I will kill him again
是的,是我杀了他,我恨不得再宰他一遍
Once was enough, dear,take her to downtown Come on
一次就够了,亲爱的 抓她回城里去,快点!
This way, honey
看这边,亲爱的
Oh, come on, it's a shame to hide such a beautiful face
哦,真是的 这么漂亮的脸蛋遮住了就太可惜了
Why did you shoot him?
你为何开枪打死他?
Why don't you give a profile, a little smile like the girl in the toothpaste ad?
来张侧面照吧! 像牙膏广告里的女郎一样笑一个如何?
That one you can't, take this down
别拍了,记录一下我的话吧
District attorney Harrison says this is a hanging case
地方检查官哈里逊起诉为绞刑案件
- I'm ready to go to the Jury tomorrow - What do you mean hanging?
我准备明天召集陪审团 你说绞刑是什么意思?
Take her down to the Cook County Jail
带她到库克郡立监狱
Come on ,sweetie headliner. Why did you shoot him? Was he crude, did he beat you, did he fool around..
快说,头条甜心,你为何开枪打死他? 是他对你无礼、打你,还是骗了你?
What do you mean hanging?
你说绞刑是什么意思?
Morphine, opium, cocaine?
吗啡、鸦片、古柯硷?
Arm length: 31 inches
手臂长度: 31寸
The matron's on the way, so don't ge too cozy
典狱长马上到了,所以别太懒散
Put off that cigarette
烟熄掉
Ever had morphine before?
以前注射过吗啡吗?
She's fine
她人很好
As long as you keep her happy
只要你一直让她保持开心
And now, ladies and gentlemen
现在,各位先生女士
The keeper of the keys, the countess of the clink
钥匙之主、监狱之花
The mistress of Murderer's row Matron "Mama" Morton
杀人犯统治者-- 女典狱长"妈妈"莫顿出场了
Ask any of the chickies in my pen
随便问我牢里的任何小鸡们
They'll tell I'm the biggest mother hen
都说我是最伟大的母鸡
I love 'em all and all of them love me
我爱他们,他们也都爱我
Because the system works
因为此体系发挥效力
The system called reciprocity
此体系称作相互关系
On your feet
站起来!
Welcome, ladies
欢迎,小姐们
Got a little motto
有句小小座右
Always sees me through
一直助我渡过难关
When you're good to Mama
你对妈妈好
Mama's good to you!
妈妈也会对你好的!
Might think it'll make your life a living hell
你们可能以为在此生活有如地狱一般
Which is just not true
那不是真的
There's a lot of favors
有几个忙
I'm prepared to do
我打算帮你们
You do one for Mama
你帮妈妈一个忙
She'll do one for you
妈妈她也会帮你一个忙
Like to be your friend if you let me
要是你们愿意,可以当我是朋友
So if something upsets you or makes you unhappy in any way
所以要是有什么惹你生气或不愉快的话
Don't shoot your fat-ass mouth on me
别把怒气指向我
Cause I don't give a shit, now move it out
因为我可不买帐,现在出去吧
They say that life is tit for tat
据说人生就是以牙还牙
And that's the way I live
那便是我的生活方式
So, I deserve a lot of tat
所以,我理该获得些回报
For what I've got to give
报答我所付出的
Don't you know that this hand
你难道不懂这支手
Washes that one too
也同样洗另一支手吗?
When you're good to Mama
你对妈妈好
Mama's good to you!
妈妈就对你好!
Let's go
走吧
You must be Hart
你一定是哈特
Ain't you a pretty one?
你满漂亮的嘛!
Thank you, madam
谢谢,夫人
Oh no, call me Mama
哦,不,喊我妈妈
I'm gonna take care of you
我会好好照顾你的
Now you'll be happy taken down in this block
你在牢里会过的很快乐的
Murderer's Row we call
我们称为凶手排
Is that nicer?
那会好点吗?
No, I don't think I really belong in here
不,我认为我真的不该属於这里
I didn't actually do anything wrong
我真的没有做错事
I need to tell you, honey
我必须告诉你,亲爱的
I never heard of a man getting killed when he didn't get just what would come at all
我没听过哪个男人会被人莫名其妙杀掉
Hey, Mama
嘿,妈妈
Come here, come here
过来一下,过来一下
Velma Kelly?
薇玛凯莉?
You're the Velma Kelly
你是薇玛凯莉
You know I was there that night I was there that night
你知道吗? 那晚我也在那里 你被捕那晚我也在那里
Yeah, you and half of Chicago
对,你和半数芝加哥人
Look at this, Mama
瞧瞧这个,妈妈
An editorial denouce me in Red Book Magazine
语录杂志有篇公然抨击我的报导
Not a memory did we reall so fiendish horrible a double homicide
如此残忍可怕的双尸命案令人不堪回想
Baby, you couldn't buy that kind of publicity
宝贝,你不能买那种公开刊物
Couldn't buy it?
不能买吗?
I guess I can keep this then
那我想我这个就省下来了
Let's try
我来想想办法
If you want my gravy
想喝肉汤的话
Pepper my ragout
帮我的炖肉洒些胡椒
Spice it up for Mama
替妈妈弄得香喷喷的
She'll get hot for you
妈妈也会报以热情
When they pass that basket
当他们推过篮子
Folks contribute to
大家把衣服丢进去
You put in for Mama
你帮妈妈丢进去
She'll pull out for you
妈妈也会帮你拿出来
The folks atop the ladder
梯顶上的人
Are the ones the world adores
受世人崇拜
So boost me up my ladder, kid
推我上去我的梯子,孩子
And I'll boost you up yours
我也会推你上去你的梯子
Let's all stroke together
让我们共同划桨
Like the Princeton crew
如同普林斯顿水手
When you're strokin' Mama
你替妈妈划桨
Mama's strokin' you
妈妈也会替你划桨
So what's the one conclusion
那么结论是
I can bring this number to?
我能主宰一切
When you're good to Mama
你对妈妈好
Mama's good to you
妈妈也会对你好
Mama
妈妈
It's kind of freezing in here
这里头有点冷
You don't think maybe there's something wrong with the heat
你想会不会是暖气出了问题?
Not that I'm complaining, mind you, but you know
我不是在抱怨,只是提醒你一下 你应该　解的
If you got a couple of blankets to sleep with
能不能给张毛毯让我盖著睡?
Lights out, ladies
熄灯了,小姐们
OK
好吧
Pop
吹
Six
六个
Squish
格吱声
Uh-Uh
啊-啊
Cicero
西塞罗
Lipschitz!
莱布尼兹
And now the six merry murderesses of the Cook County Jail
现在这库克郡立监狱的 六个快乐女杀人犯
in their rendition of the "Cell Block Tango."
联合演出"牢笼探戈"
Pop
吹
Six
六个
Squish
格吱声
Uh-uh
啊-啊
Cicero
西瑟罗
Lipschitz
莱布尼兹
Pop, six, squish, uh-uh, cicero
吹、六个、格吱声、啊-啊、西塞罗
He had it coming
他自作自受
He only had himself to blame
他只能怪他自己
If you'd have been there
如果你在那里
If you'd have seen it
如果你有看到
I betcha you would have done the same!
我敢说你也会那样子做
Pop, six, squish, uh-uh, cicero, lipschitz
吹、六个、格吱声、啊-啊、 西瑟罗、莱布尼兹
You know how people have these little habits that get you down
你晓得人们如何染上这些小小恶习吗?
Like Bernie. Bernie liked to chew gum.
譬如说柏尼吧,柏尼喜欢嚼口香糖
No, not chew. Pop.
不,不是嚼,是用吹的
So I came home this one day and I'm really irritated,
有一天我回到家,我真的火冒三丈
I'm looking for a little sympathy
我只冀求一点小小怜悯
and there's Bernie lyin' on the couch
柏尼躺在沙发上
drinkin' a beer and chewin' it
喝著啤酒,嚼著口香糖
No, not chewin'. Poppin'
不对,不是嚼,是吹
So, I said my six, you pop that gum one more time
所以,我说六个啊 你再吹一次口香糖看看
And he did
他真的吹了
So I took the shotgun off the wall
所以我拿起墙上的散弹枪
and I fired two warning shots
我开了两枪以示警惕
into his head
打中他的头
He had it coming
他自作自受
He only had himself to blame
只能怪他自己
If you'd have been there
如果你在那里
If you'd have heard it
如果你有听到
I betcha you would have done the same!
我敢说你也会那样子做
I met Ezekiel Young from Salt Lake City about two years ago
约两年前,我遇见来自盐湖城的伊斯库杨
and he told me he was single
他告诉我他还是单身汉
and we hit it off right away.
我们一拍即合
So, we started living together
因此,我们开始住在一块
He'd go to work, he'd come home,
他上班、回家
I'd fix him a drink, and we'd have dinner
我端饮料给他,并共进晚餐
And then I found out
後来我发现...
"Single" he told me?
他告诉我他是"单身"
Single, my ass
单身? 才怪!
Not only was he married
不只他已婚
oh no
哦,不
He had six wives
他有六个老婆
One of those Mormons, you know
一个摩门教徒,你懂吧?
So that night when he came home from work
所以当晚他下班回家後
I fixed him his drink as usual
像平常一样端上饮料给他
You know, some guys just can't hold their arsenic
你知道的,有些家伙就是无法承受砷毒
He had it coming
他自作自受
He took a flower in its prime
他摘下全盛时期的花朵
And then he used it
接著利用过之後
And he abused it
便百般凌辱
It was a murder But not a crime
那是谋杀,不过不是罪
Now, I'm standing in the kitchen
我站在厨房里
carvin' up the chicken for dinner
剁著鸡肉好当晚餐
minding my own business
一心一意做著自己的事
In storms my husband Wilbur in a jealous rage
我老公威伯打翻了醋坛子
"You been screwin' the milkman," he says
他说:「你一直和送牛奶员乱搞」
He was crazy
他疯了
and he kept on screamin' "You been screwin' the milkman,"
他一直喊著「你一直和送牛奶员乱搞」
And then he ran into my knife!
後来我便拿把刀子杀了他!
He ran into my knife ten times
连刺十刀!
If you'd have been there
如果你在那里
If you'd have seen it
如果你有看到
I betcha you would have done the same
我敢说你也会那样子做
Mit keresek, enn itt? Azt mondjok, hogy lakem lefogta a ferjemet
(外语)
Yeah, but did you do it
是的,不过是你干的吗?
Ah ah, not guilty
啊-啊,无罪
He had it coming
他自作自受
My sister, Veronica, and I did this double act
我妹妹薇若妮卡和我从事二人组表演
and my husband, Charlie, traveled around with us
而我老公查理周旋在我们两人之间
Now for the last number in our act
在我们最後一场表演
we did these 20 acrobatic tricks in a row
我俩轮流演出这20次表演
one, two, three, four, five
1,2,3,4,5
Splits, spread eagles, back flips, flip flops
张翼,大鹏展翅,往後振翅,不断拍动
One right after the other
双翼此起彼落
So this one night before the show we are down at the Hotel Cicero
所以在表演前一晚,我们下榻西瑟罗旅馆
the three of us boozin' , havin' a few laughs
三人把酒寻欢、其乐无比
and we run out of ice
而冰块用光了
so I go out to get some
所以我出去买一些
I come back, open the door
我回来後,一打开门
And there's Veronica and Charlie doing Number Seventeen
薇若妮卡和查理正在17号房里办事
the spread eagle
大鹏展翅
Well, I was in such a state of shock
哦,当时有如晴天霹雳
I completely blacked out
陷入一片昏厥
I can't remember a thing
我什么也记不得了
It wasn't until later, when I was washing the blood off my hands
直到事後我清洗双手上的血渍时
I even knew they were dead
才惊觉他们已经死了
They had it coming
他们自作自受
They had it coming all along
他们一直自作自受
I didn't do it
我没有干
But if I'd done it
但要是我干了
How could you tell me that I was wrong?
又怎能说我错了呢?
They had it coming
他们自作自受
They had it coming all along
他们一直自作自受
I didn't do it
我没有干
But if I'd done it
但要是我干了
How could you tell me that I was wrong?
又怎能说我错了呢?
I love Alvin Lipschitz More than I can possibly say
我爱艾文莱布尼兹胜过言语所能形容
He was a real artistic guy
他是个真正的艺术家
Sensitive...a painter
多愁善感的...画家
But he was always trying to find himself
但他一直想找寻自我
He'd go out every night looking for himself and along the way
他夜夜外出沿路寻找自我
he found Ruth, Gladys, Rosemary and Irving
结果找到露丝、葛蕾蒂、萝丝玛莉和尔薇
I guess you can say we broke up because of artistic differences
我猜你会说我们分手是因为审美观差异
He saw himself as alive and I saw him dead
他看到的是活生生的自己 可我看到的是死翘翘的他
The dirty bum, bum, bum, bum, bum
下流胚子...
They had it comin'
他们自作自受
They had it comin' all along
他们一直自作自受
'Cause if they used us
若是他们利用过我们
And they abused us
便百般凌辱
How could you tell us That we were wrong?
又怎能说我们错了呢?
He had it coming
他自作自受
He only had himself to blame
只能怪他自己
If you'd have been there
如果你在那里
If you'd have seen it
如果你有看到
I betcha you would have done the same
我敢说你也会那样子做
- You pop that gum one more time - Single my ass - Ten times
你再吹一次口香糖试试看 是单身才怪!  连刺十刀
-Miert csukott Uncle Sam bortonbe. - Number Seventeen - the spread eagle. - Artistic differences
17号房...大鹏展翅...审美观差异
Pop
吹
Six
六个
Squish
格吱声
Uh-uh
啊-啊
Cicero
西瑟罗
Lipschitz
莱布尼兹
Who brought them?
谁拿来的?
What's up to you?
你怎么了?
Nothing
没什么
Heard they're Velma's
听说是薇玛的
Yeah, Hanja does all her laundry for a couple of weeks
是的,韩雅帮她洗好几个礼拜了
- Fresh towels for change - Make it quick
送乾净的换洗毛巾 动作俐落点!
I can take good care of you
我会好好照顾你的
There're a couple of things Let me analyze to you
我分析几件事给你听
Now, Billy Flynn set your trial date on Mar 5th
好了,比利弗林定3月5日审理你的案件
Mar 7th you would be aquitted
3月7日你就会被宣判无罪
On Mar 8th, you know what Mama's gonna do for you?
3月8日,你知道妈妈要怎么对你吗?
Mama's gonna put you back in Veaudeville Circus
妈妈会送你回维德威尔表演团
So now you're an agent too?
那现在你也成了情报员?
Well them until Mabelle install a private line in your cell All calls gotta go through me
玛贝莉在你们牢房装了监视线路 所有电话都会经过我这里
What kind of dough we're talking about?
我们在谈什么钱啊?
You know, this crazy world
你明白这个疯狂世界
I mean, Babe Ruth is wearing rules and playing in palace for 5000 dollars for a week
我意思是,露丝一周赚5000元 生活多惬意
Yeah, what about someone with real talent
对,那真正有才华的人怎么办?
Well, I can talk to the boys over Wienworks
嗯,我可以跟威恩沃斯那些人谈
With your recent sensation activities
利用你最近的轰动事件
They seem they can give you 2500
他们差不多会付给你2500元
2500?
2500元?
Geez, the most me and Veronica make was 350
天啊,我和薇若妮卡最高也不过才赚350元
Yeah, that was what happens when you have that Redbook presentation
没错,你若登上语录杂志就是那样
You know what, Mama?
你知道吗,妈妈?
I always wanted to play Big Jim
我一直想演出"大吉姆"
Do you think you can get me that?
你认为你能帮我争取到吗?
Big Jim's?
"大吉姆"? 对
I don't know
我不知道
It's gonna take another phone call
还得再打通电话
How much is that gonna cost?
那得花多少钱?
Come on Vel
好了,薇玛
I feel about you, you're like family of me You're one of my own
我很同情你,你好比我的家人 都是自己人了
- I'll do for fifty bucks - Fifty bucks for a phone call?
50元我就办 一通电话50元?
You must get a lot of wrong numbers, Mama
你一定会故意打错一堆号码,妈妈
Oh, Ms. Kelly, got your personals
哦,凯莉小姐,你的内衣物洗好了
Freshly pressed by yours truly
有洗乾净熨平了
I know, it's my pleasure
我懂,这是我的荣幸
Hey, listen
嘿,听著
Can I ask you something?
我能问你些事吗?
You know that Harrison guy?
你认识那个叫哈里逊的家伙吗?
Well he said what I have done is a hanging case
他说我犯的案要被处绞刑
And he's prepared to ask for the maximum penalty
而且他准备求处最高刑责
Yeah, so?
是认识又怎样?
So I'm scared
所以我很怕
I surely would appreciate some advice
给点建议的话,我会感激不尽
Especially from...
尤其是来自...
Someone I admire as much as you
一个我极度崇拜的人口中说出来
Since I can remember, I have wanted to be on the stage
自我有记忆以来,一直好想登台表演
Really?
真的?
What's your talent, washing and drying?
你会做什么? 洗衣、烫衣吗?
No, no
不,不是的
I dance in the chorus
我在合唱团时跳过
That was before I met my husband Amos
是遇见我老公艾默斯之前的事了
Look, you want some advice?
听著,你想要建议吗?
Here it is, direct from me to you
好的,我就对你直说吧
Keep your paws off my underwear. OK?
继续洗我的内衣物,好吗?
Yeah, OK
是,没问题
Thanks
谢了
For nothing
毫无帮忙
She's not that nice, ain't she?
她口气不太好,是吧?
I'll tell you no matter how big she gives, she's still as common as ever
我告诉你不论她名气多响 她还是跟以前一样没变
I'd like to help you, deary
我愿意帮你,亲爱的
We'll take a lotto
我们来算机率
So what do you figure on useful ground?
你要怎样采取有利的立场?
Grounds?
立场?
What're you gonna tell the jury?
你要怎么回答陪审团?
Who's figure, I'll tell them the truth
不用想,我会实话实说
The truth?
实话实说?
That's one way ticket to the death house
那便是死路一条了
Holy mother of God
天杀的
Oh relax
哦,别紧张
I mean, in this town Murders are for entertainment
我意思是,在这个城里 发生命案是常有的事
Besides, in 47 years, the Cook County never hung a woman yet
而且,这47年来 库克郡立监狱没吊死过任何女人
So that's 47 to 1
所以他们不会吊死你的机率是47比1
Jesus, Mary and Joseph
老天,玛莉和约瑟夫
You're talking to the wrong people
你找错对象谈了
What you need is Billy Flynn
你该找的是比利弗林
Who?
谁?
Billy Flynn
比利弗林
He's only the best criminal lawyer in all over Illinois
他是全伊利诺州最厉害的刑案律师
Tell me what he don't know about juries and women
对陪审团和女人心态　如指掌
How do you get this Billy Flynn?
你要怎么联络这位比利弗林?
Well, not by prayer, deary
嗯,可不是靠祈祷的,亲爱的
First you give me a hundred dollars
首先你得付我100元
Then I'll make a phone call
然後我会帮你打电话
Hundred dollars? Well it just...
100元? 嗯,只不过是...
I mean
我是说
Seems pretty steep for a phone call
一通电话似乎贵了点
Oh but it worth every cent
哦,不过保证值回票¤
I mean he never lost a case for female clients yet
我意思是他替女性客户打官司还未败诉过
Or a sweet puss like you as well
或者像你这么可爱的小妞
Let's just say it seems so blind in Chicago
姑且说在芝加哥似乎很盲目吧
He's never lost a case?
他没败诉过?
Never
没有
Every girl in this place would kill to have Billy Flynn represent her
这里每个女的都希望比利弗林帮她辩护
We want Billy
我们...要...比利
B. I. Double L. Y.
B-I-两个L-Y
We're all his
我们都是他的了
He's our kind of a guy
他真是我们的男子汉
And ooh what luck
多么地幸运啊!
'Cause here he is
因为他来了
Ladies and Gentleman, presenting the Silver-Tongued Prince of the Courtroom
先生女士们,现在出场的是 法庭之怠舌王子
the one, the only Billy Flynn
举世无双的比利弗林
I don't care about expensive things
我不在乎穿金戴怠等昂贵东西
Cashmere coats, diamond rings
羊毛大衣、钻戒
Don't mean a thing
一点意义也没有
All I care about is love
我只在乎爱情
(Billy) That's what I'm here for (Girls) That's what he's here for
那便是我此行目的 那便是他此行目的
I don't care for wearing silk cravats
我不在乎是否有围丝质　巾
Ruby studs, satin spats
红宝石钮扣、绸缎绑腿
Don't mean a thing
一点意义也没有
All I care about is love
我只在乎爱情
All he cares about is love
他只在乎爱情
Give me two eyes of blue
我要她有对蓝眼珠
Softly saying, "I need you"
轻柔地说声「我　要你」 我　要你!
Let me see her standin' there
让我看见她伫立在那里
And honest, mister, I'm a millionaire
坦白说,我是个百万富翁
I don't care for any fine attire
我不在乎穿不穿上等服装
Vanderbilt might admire
穿牛仔裤也不错
No, no, not me
不,不,不是我
All I care about is love
我只在乎爱情
All he cares about is love
他只在乎爱情
Good morning, ladies
早安,小姐们
That's what he's here for
那便是他此行目的
Excuse me, gentlemen
抱歉,先生
Ms. Kelly, do you remember anything at all about that night
凯莉小姐,你还记得当晚发生的事吗?
I passed out completely, Ms. Sunshine I can' t remember a thing
我完全昏过去了,珊珊小姐 所以我一点都记不得了
Only that I didn't do it
只记得不是我干的
- Any idea who did it? - No
知道是谁干的吗? 不知道
No but my client is offering a substantial award to anyone with information about this crime
不知道,但我当事人提供一大笔赏金 给任何提供犯罪线索的人
How much is the reward, Ms. Kelly?
赏金有多少,凯莉小姐?
I don't know, how much?
不清楚,多少?
I'll work it out after the trial
等审判後再来处理
Now, if there's no more questions, Ms. Kelly and I had a lot work to do
好了,要是没有问题了的话 凯莉小姐跟我还有一大堆事要办
What's all this about the awards?
赏金的事到底怎么回事?
Often done before. If the reporters write it on we deny the whole thing later on
这招以前常用,要是记者报导出来 我们稍候完全否认就行了
Thank you
谢谢
All he cares about is love
他只在乎爱情
- Mr. Flynn, I'm Roxie...Hart - Who?
弗林先生,我叫萝西...哈特 谁?
- Mama tells you about me - Oh, yeah right, right, the cute one
妈妈跟你提过我 哦,没错,没错,小甜甜
How would I hope that you might represent me
我希望你能帮我辩护
You have five thousand dollars?
你有5000元吗?
That's a lot of money
那是好大一笔钱
Mama didn't say anything about five thousand dollars
妈妈没提到5000元的事
Look it, eh, Mr. Flynn
听著,嗯,弗林先生
I'm not good at this sort of thing
我不擅长这种事
Maybe we could make some sort of arrangements between us
也许我们之间可以作些安排
I could be awfully a good sport
我也是个做事相当乾脆的人
Good you got that idea of our system
很好,你很上道
Now listen
现在听好
You mean just one thing to me
你对我而言只有一种意义
You call me when you got five thousand dollars
等你筹到5000元再来找我
All he cares about is love
他只在乎爱情
Show me long raven hair
要有长长乌黑的秀发
Flowin' down, about to there
长发飘逸,长度约到那里
When I see her runnin' free
我看著她自由自在地奔跑
Keep your money, that's enough for me
钱你留著自己用,我已经够多了
I don't care for drivin' Packard cars
我不在乎是否开派克汽车
Or smoking long buck cigars
或者抽高级雪茄
No, no, not me
不,不,不是我
All I care about is
我只在乎...
Doin' the guy in
成为...
Who's pickin', on you
雀屏中选的人
Twistin' the wrist
转转手腕
That's turnin' the screw
旋转螺丝
All I care about
我所在乎的
Is love
只是爱情
Oh you'll see him now
哦,你可以见他了
- Well, hello, Andy - Amos, my name is Amos
你好,安迪 艾默斯,我叫艾默斯
That's right, take a seat
没错,请坐吧
You know, you're a remarkable man
你知道吗? 你真是个了不起的男人
Your wife two times you, plug the guy and tries to pity on you
你老婆多次和男人勾搭,还想让你可怜她
Most men are gonna dim with that swing, but no
多半男人都不想张扬出去,可你却不是
You're sticking by her
依然护著她
Actually hero in my eyes
我觉得你是真正的英雄
That's right
没错
I'm a hero
我是英雄
Did you bring the money?
钱你带来了吗?
I didn't do as well as I hoped, but
我不像我期望中做的那样好,不过...
I will, Mr. Flynn, I will
我会的,弗林先生,我会的
Ah, this is only a thousand
啊,这里只有1000元
Plus the three hundred I borrowed from the guy down at the garage
我另外还跟修车厂同事借了300元
and there are seven...
还有7...
Seven hundred from the building of Loan Fund
700元是跟融资大楼贷来的
Two thousand?
2000元?
And that's all I got so far
目前我只能筹到这么多
But I'll give twenty dollars off my salary every week
但我会从每周薪水扣除20元给你
I'll give you notes with interest, double triple until every cent is paid, I promise
我会连同利息一块给你 直到每分钱都还清楚为止,我发誓
When you came to me yesterday
你昨天来找我的时候
I didn't ask you if she was guilty
我没问你她是否有罪
I didn't ask if she was innocent
也没问你她是否无辜
I didn't ask if she was a drunk, or a dopefing, no
我没问你她是否喝醉还是吸毒,没有
All I said was do you have five thousand dollars You said yes
我只问你有没有5000元,你回答说有
But you don't have five thousand dollars
但你并没有5000元
So I figure you're a dirty liar I don't waste time on dirty liars
所以我觉得你是个无耻骗子 我不想浪费时间在无耻骗子身上
Look
听著
I'm really sorry, Mr. Flynn
我真的很抱歉,弗林先生
On the other hand
另一方面...
Your devotion to your wife is really very very touching
你对你老婆的奉献真的是 非常非常让人感动
I'll take your wife's case and I'll keep it
我会接下你老婆的案子 钱我就收下了
Because I play square
因为我要玩公平一点
Now, look, Hart
你听好了,哈特
I don't like to blow my own horn
不是我自吹自擂
But believe me, if Jesus Christ lived in Chicago today if he had five thousand dollars
但相信我,如果耶稣基督活在今日芝加哥 只要他有5000元的话
And he come to me, things would've turned out differently
照样来找我,情况就不同了
All right, this is what we gonna do
好了,我们要做的是
By the end of the week, I wanna have Roxie's name in the front page of every newspaper in town
本周末之前,我要教萝西的名字 登上各大报纸头版
Sweetest Little Jazz Killer Ever Lived in Chicago
甜美的小爵士凶手曾住在芝加哥
That's the angle I'm after
那就是我的看法
You make the announcement, we're gonna have an auction
你发布消息,就说我们要举办个拍卖会
Tell them we gotta raise money for her defense
告诉人们我们要筹款帮她辩护
They'll buy everything she's ever touched, everything
那人们就会买她用的每样东西
Your shoes, your dresses, your perfume, your underwear
鞋子、衣服、香水、内衣物
Mm, the troller records like the one I was playing when I shot the bastard
还有像我现在播放的唱片转盘
I didn't hear that
我没听懂
Not that I didn't have ground mind you Hey what are they?
并非我没有立场提醒你 嘿,是什么?
That's when we go to trial
在开庭的时候
Look, nobody, nobody's gonna care a lick
听著,没有人会在乎的
Watch your defenses unless they care about you
除非他们同情你,否则得小心答辩
So the first thing we're gonna do is to work out some sympathy from the press
所以你首先要做的是博取媒体同情
I'm not pretty sure like Mary Sunshine
我相当讨厌玛莉珊珊
But there's one thing they can never resist
不过有件事他们无可否认
And that is, a reformed sinner
那就是一个痛改前非的罪犯
So tell me, what's your favorite subject in school
说说你在学校最喜欢的科目
- Dalf, that was a real... - There must be something that you're really good at
法语,那真是... 那一定是你最拿手的项目
Oh I got high marks in the courtesy in hygiene
哦,健教礼节这一科我分数很高
Perfect, you wanted to be a nun
太好了,你想当修女
Nun?
修女?
Where were you born?
你在哪出世?
On a chicken farm outside Lurburk
在拉柏克外一处养鸡农场
Beautiful and silent home for every luxury and refinement
改为出生在美丽详和的家庭
Where are your parents now?
你父母现在人在哪?
Probably on front porch in their rocking chairs
可能坐在前院走廊摇椅上
Parents are dead
改为父母都死了
Family fortune swept away you're educated in the Sacred Heart
家财万贯,而你就读圣心学校
Then you fell into a run away marriage, left you miserable alone
接著你便闪电结婚 将悲惨日子抛的远远地
Unhappy, of course you got swept up in the mad world of the city
不快乐,你当然会被遗忘在 这疯狂世界城市里
Jazz, Cabaret, liquor, you're drawn like a moth to the flame - A moth?
爵士、歌舞表演、美酒 你像飞蛾扑火般沉溺下去.  飞蛾?
Now the mad world acceased, and you are the butterfly
如今这疯狂世界 你就是蝴蝶
Crushed on the wheel
惨死在轮子下
Which is it, is it the moth or the butterfly?
哪一种? 飞蛾还是蝴蝶?
- You have sinned in your sorrow - God that's beautiful
你已悔过自新 老天,那太棒了
Cut off God, stay where you're acquitted
别管上帝了,你会无罪开释的
Kid, when I'm through with you not only will you be acquitted
孩子,等我和你谈完了 不但会获判无罪
Every man in jury wanna take you home to meet his mother
每个陪审团男子都想带你回家让母亲看
- I was born in a beautiful southern combat - What?
我生於一处美丽的南方 什么?
Oh holy shit Oh I'll never get this straight
哦,该死 哦,我老是念不顺
Pipe down and swearing
安静,宣誓
Look, from now on You say nothing about of damn
听著,从现在起 你不可以骂脏话
Now try again
现在再讲一次
I was born on a...
我出生於...
Come on, come on
快点,快点
So what's the most thing I'm gonna do in  the witness stand
那我在证人席上最重要是该怎么做
I thought I'd get all teary eyed
我想我会痛哭流涕
And ask for your handkerchief
跟你要手帕
Then I thought I'll take a peek at the Jury like this
接著我想我会像这样瞄著陪审团
Flashing a bit thigh, hah?
露出一点大腿
What do you think?
你觉得呢?
Sounds great
听起来不错
Hey, don't you wanna hear the rest?
嘿,想不想听其它的?
Come on, I'll get up, you can talk from my lists
好啦,我会起身 等我问到你时,你再回答问题
Well, well, well
好,好,好
Sorry to be late, Mr. Flynn
抱歉来迟了,弗林先生
Hope you're not too bored
希望没让你等得太无聊
I like it
我喜欢
Hey, Pauliana, I heard your press conference is tomorrow
嘿,宝莉安娜,听说你明天要开记者会
Yeah, what's up to you?
是啊,干你什么事?
Well you wanted my advice right?
你不是要我的建议吗?
Well here it is
我的建议是...
Don't forget Bailiff's No. 1 client is Billy Flynn
别忘了副司法官的头号当事人 就是比利弗林
Meaning what?
什么意思?
Meaning
意思是...
Don't let him hug the spotlight
别让他成为媒体焦点
You're the one they paid to see
你才是他们争相目睹的人
Now remember, we can only sell them one idea a time
你记住,我们一次只能回答一个问题
Yeah, I can still see him coming after me with that awful look in his eyes
是的,我仍可见他用那可怕眼神追著我
And?
然後呢?
And we both reach for the gun
我俩同时抢到枪
That's right, you both reach for the gun
没错,你俩同时抢到枪
Ready?
准备好没?
Yeah
好了
Gentlemen, gentlemen, Ms. Sunshine
各位,各位,珊珊小姐
My client's just entered a plead of not guilty
我当事人正要做无罪抗辩
We look forward to the trial at the earliest possible date. Now is there any questions?
我们期盼早日开庭审理 现在谁还有问题?
Ms. Sunshine
珊珊小姐
As you know, my paper is dry
你怎么知道我想问?
Do you any advice for young girls seeking to avoid a life of Jazz and drink
你可有忠告给那些少女们 让她们避免步入同样爵士酗酒的生活呢?
Absolutely yes.
绝对有
Mrs. Hart feels that it's the tragic combination of liquor and Jazz
哈特太太觉得是酒精加爵士後的悲剧组合
which led her to the downfall. Next question
才导致她现在这种下场 下一个问题
Ladies and gentlemen
先生女士们
I would just like to state how flattered I am that you came to see you
我只想说我真的受宠若惊 你们抢著来看我
Mrs. Hart is very...
哈特太太非常...
You see I was a moth crushed on the wheel
你们明白我就像飞蛾撞上轮子
You know, a butterfly drawn to the, to the...
你知道的,像蝴蝶淹死在...在...
I bet you wanna know why I shot the bastard
我敢说你们一定想知道 我为何开枪打死那混蛋
Shut up, dummy
闭嘴,笨蛋
Mr. Billy Flynn in the "Press Conference Rag"
比利弗林先生在"记者会上发飙"
notice how his mouth never moves - almost
注意一下他的嘴巴没有动...几乎没动
Where'd you come from?
你从哪来的?
Mississippi
密西西比州
And your parents?
你的父母呢?
Very wealthy.
非常有钱
Where are they now?
他们现在人呢?
Six feet under. But she was granted one more start
六尺黄泉之下 不过应给她一个改过自新的机会
The convent of the sacred heart!
就读圣心修道学院!
When'd you get here?
你何时来此地?
How old were you?
你多大年纪?
Don't remember
不记得了
Then what happened?
後来发生什么事?
I met Amos And he stole my heart away
我遇见艾默斯,他偷走了我的心
Convinced me to elope one day
有一天说服了我和他一块私奔
Oh, poor dear, I can't believe what you've been through
哦,真可怜,我真不敢相信你的遭遇
A convent girl! A run-away marriage!
一个修道学院女孩! 一段私奔的婚姻!
Now tell us Roxie
现在告诉我们,萝西
Who's Fred Casely?
佛瑞德凯斯利是谁?
My ex-boyfriend
我的前任男友
Why'd you shoot him
你为何开枪打死他?
I was leavin'
我想离开他
Was he angry?
他很生气?
Like a madman! Still I said, "Fred, move along."
像疯了似的! 我还是说:「佛瑞德,你走吧!」
She knew that she was doin' wrong
她明白自己做错了
Then describe it
请描述一下
He came toward me.
他来找我
With a pistol?
身上带了手枪?
From my bureau
从我抽屉取出的
Did you fight him?
你有反抗他吗?
Like a tiger
像老虎一般
He had strength and she had none
他力大无穷,而她娇弱无比
And yet we both reached for the gun
我俩同时抢到那把枪
Oh yes, oh yes, oh yes we both Oh yes, we both
哦,是的...我俩同时 哦,是的,我俩同时
Oh yes, we both reached for the gun
哦,是的,我俩同时抢到那把枪
the gun, the gun, the gun
枪,枪,枪
Understandable, understandable
明白,明白了
Yes, it's perfectly understandable
是的,非常明白了
Comprehensible, comprehensible
解,　解了
Not a bit reprehensible
不该受此谴责
It's so defensible!
自卫有理!
How you're feeling?
你觉得怎样?
Very frightened
非常可怕
Are you sorry?
你觉得後悔吗?
Are you kidding?
开什么玩笑?!
What's your statement?
你的供词呢?
All I'd say is
我只想说...
Though my choo-choo jumped the track
虽然我一时偏差犯错
I'd give my life to bring him back
我愿用我生命换他回来
- And? - Stay away from
然後呢? 远离...
- What? - Jazz and liquor
什么? 爵士和酒精
- And? - And the man who
还有呢? 以及这种...
-What? - Play for fun
什么? 感情骗子
- And what? - That's the thought that
再来呢? 那就是我目前...
- Yeah! - Came upon me
对! ...所能想到的
- When? - When we both reached for the gun!
什么时候? 当我俩同时抢到枪时!
Understandable, understandable
明白,明白了
Yes, it's perfectly understandable
是的,非常明白了
Comprehensible, comprehensible
解,　解了
Not a bit reprehensible
不该受此谴责
It's so defensible!
自卫有理!
Oh yes, oh yes, oh yes they both
哦,是的! 哦,是的! 哦,是的,他们俩
Oh yes they both
哦,是的,他们俩
- Reach for the gun - Let me hear it
同时抢到枪 大声点
Oh yes, they both reached For the gun
哦,是的,他们俩同时
For the gun.
抢到枪
A little louder!
再大声一点!
Oh yes, oh yes, oh yes they both
哦,是的! 哦,是的! 哦,是的,他们俩
Oh yes they both
哦,是的,他们俩同时
Oh yes they both reach for the gun
哦,是的,他们俩同时抢到枪
Now you got it
现在你懂了吧?
Oh yes, oh yes oh yes  they both
哦,是的! 哦,是的! 哦,是的,他们俩
Oh yes they both
哦,是的,他们俩同时
Oh yes they both reach for the gun
哦,是的,他们俩同时抢到枪
Both reach for the gun
同时抢到枪
Move all by a capone
感动了所有市民
The windy city has taken a new criminal to a talk
满城闹得风风雨雨
The name on everybody's lips is Roxie Hart
人人都在讨论萝西哈特的事
The sweetest little lady ever accused of murder in Chicago
这位最可爱的小姐在芝加哥被控谋杀
Women wanna look like her
女人想变得跟她一样装扮
Fellows wanna go out with her
男人想约她出去
Some little girls even wanna take her home
有些小女孩甚至想带她回家
Don't get any ideas, little lady
别胡思乱想了,小姐
On the other side of town
在城的另一边
The assistant DA promises the keen shant shootre shall swing before the year is up
检察官DA保证至少判刑一年以上
Who knows?
谁晓得呢?
If he lives up to his word, assistant DA Harrison might become Governor Harrison some day
要是他说到做到,哈里森检察官 可能有天会成为哈里森州长
Back at the scene of the crime
回到犯罪现场
Everybody wants a little piece of Roxie Hart
大家都想拥有萝西哈特的东西
This jar of colgraine sent her husband back 20 dollars
这位贾柯琳寄回她丈夫20元
Maybe this pretty little lady would get some of that famous Roxie style
也许这位漂亮小妞能帮那 家喻户晓的萝西小姐设计个造型
It seems everybody these days is ruling for
最近似乎人人都在讨论著...
Roxie Hart
萝西哈特
Take off these flowers and make sure they do send them
拿走这些花,确认他们有送过去
So, kiddo
那么,孩子
You've any thought what you wann do after Billy get you off
在比利这件事过後,你想做什么?
Yeah,  I think I'd like to go on the stage
是的,我想继续登台表演
Yeah, figure it as much
对,心想事成
I've already called the Morris office
我已经打过电话到莫里斯办公室了
Really? How much is that gonna cost me?
真的? 那我得花多少钱?
Very fair to do, ten percent of all your takings
¤钱非常公道,你全部收入的一成
Yeah, we'll see, Mama
对,我们等著瞧,妈妈
Besides, I don't even have an act yet
此外,我好像还没得到演出呢
Well, killing Fred Caseley was your act
嗯,杀了佛瑞德是你的表演
May not ??? audience ???
那是观众的独跳舞步 那是我最喜欢的一首歌
It's a freak act
那可真是怪了
Besides
另外
Hi
嗨
I'm better than that
我比那还棒
Of course you are, cup cake
你当然没问题,轻而易举
I mean you may be as big as Sophie Tago
我意思是你可能和苏菲塔果一样有名
You really think so?
你真这么认为?
Made Canton and Joseph can buy
坎顿和约瑟夫可能会相信
You know I always wanted to have my name on those papers
你知道我一直很想我的名字上报
You know before I met Amos
你知道在我遇见艾默斯之前
I used to date with this well to do ugly bootlegger
我曾跟有钱、长相很丑的私酒贩子交往
He used to like to take me out and show me off
他曾想带我出去炫耀一番
Ugly guys like to do that
丑男喜欢那样做
Once it's said in the paper
报纸曾登出来
Gamelands Alcapella seen a shavito with a cute blonde
甘南艾卡培尔看见一个名人 和一位可爱金发女郎在一起
That was me
那就是我
I cliffed and I saved better
我剪下来保存好好的
You know all my life
你知道我这一生
I wanna have my own act
只想拥有自己的表演
But no, no no no no
但事与愿违
It's always no, they always turn me down
老是不从人愿、遭到拒绝
One big world full of no
世界这么大竟处处碰壁
And then Amos came along
後来艾默斯来了
Safe, sweet Amos
安全可靠又可爱的艾默斯
He never says no
他从不说不
I've never done this before
我以前没做过这事
But you know
不过你知道的
It is such a special night
在一个非常特别的夜晚
And you're such a great audience
你们真是个好听众
And I just, I really feel I can I can talk to you, you know
我只是...我真的觉得可以对你倾诉 你知道吗?
So forget what you've read in the papers
别管你在报纸上所看到的
And forget what you've heard from the radios
忘了你在广播里所听到的
Because, because
因为...因为...
Because I'm gonna tell you the truth
因为我要告诉你事实真相
Not that the truth really matters
并非真相如此重要
But I'm gonna tell you anyway
不过我就是想告诉你
On the bed of the apartment
在公寓床上
Amos was
艾默斯是
Zero
零分
I mean when he made love to me
我意思是他跟我做爱
It was like
就好比...
I think he was fixing a carburetor or something
我觉得他像在修理汽车化油器或其它零件
I like you, honey, I love you
我喜欢你,亲爱的,我爱你
Anyway
总之
I started fooling around
我开始到处闲逛
Then I started screwing around
之後便开始胡搞起来
Which is fooling around without dinner
连晚餐都不吃就四处徘徊
Then I met Fred Caseley
然後我遇见佛瑞德凯斯利
Who said that he can get me into the Veaudebill
他说他能让我进入维德毕尔
But that ain't quite work out like I've planned
但事情不照我计划一般进行
I guess it didn't really work out to grateful Fred either
我猜对佛瑞德来说也一样没有成功
So I gave up on the whole idea
所以我放弃整个想法
If you can't figure after all these use
如果这样你还想不通的话
Opportunities just pass you by
机会稍纵即逝
And now,
如今...
with this swing I get 'em all
事情进行的太顺利了
with all these publicity,
出尽风头
l got me a world full of yes!
这世界真是太棒了!
The name on everybody's lips
每个人嘴巴谈论的
Is gonna be Roxie
都是萝西
The lady rakin' in the chips
报章杂志上报导的
I'm gonna be a celebrity
我会成为名人
That means somebody everyone knows
那表示家喻户晓
They're gonna recognize my eyes
人们会认得我的眼睛
My hair, my teeth, my boobs, my nose
头发、牙齿、胸脯、　子
From just some dumb mechanic's wife
从原先某个蠢技工的妻子
I'm gonna be Roxie
摇身一变成为萝西
Who says that murder's not an art?
谁说谋杀不是种艺术?
And who in case she doesn't hang
万一没被吊死
Can say she started with a bang?
就能夸说是开了枪才红起来的?
Roxie Hart!
萝西哈特!
Boys
小伙子们!
They're gonna wait outside in line
他们会在外头排队等候
To get to see Roxie
只为了能见萝西一面
Think of those autographs I'll sign
索取我的亲笔签名照,我会签上...
"Good luck to you, Roxie"
「祝你好运,萝西 亲笔」
And I'll appear in a lavaliere
我要戴上珍珠项链出现
That goes all the way down to my waist
一直垂挂至腰间
Here a ring, there a ring Everywhere a ring a ling
这里也戴,那里也戴 戒指项链挂的满满的
But always the best of taste
但只戴有品味的
l'm a star.
我是巨星
And the audience loves me. And l love them.
观众爱我,我也爱他们
And they love me for loving them. And l love them for loving me.
他们爱我是因为我爱他们 我爱他们是因为他们爱我
And we love each other.
我们互相爱戴对方
And that's cause none of us got enough love in our childhoods.
那是因为我们的童年缺乏爱的滋润
And that's showbiz.... kid.
那就是演艺圈...小子
She's giving up her humdrum life
她不再过著平凡无奇的生活
I'm gonna be, sing it's Roxie
我会是...唱出来! 萝西
She made a scandal and a start
她以丑闻走红
And Sophie Tucker will shit, I know
我知道苏菲塔克将为之气结...
To see her name get billed below
看见她的名字排在我之下
Roxie Hart!
萝西哈特!
l just can't take it anymore.
我再也受不了
I can't go anywhere without hearing about that dumb tomato!
我没办法走到哪都听到那蠢蕃茄的事!
Oh, no Mama, not you too.
哦,不,妈妈,你不要也这样
l've got some bad news, kid. The tour has been cancelled.
我有些坏消息,孩子 巡回表演已经取消了
What?
什么?
Your name is out of the paper too long.
你的名字未上报太久了
All you read about today, is the Hart kid. She's hot.
你今天看到的都是哈特,她太红了
And what am l supposed to do? Suck up to her like everybody else?
那我该怎么做? 像其他人一样对她拍马屁吗?
lt couldn't hurt.
又不会怎样
Over my dead body.
除非我死
Mind if l join you?
我可以坐下吗?
Lights out.
熄灯
Smoke?
抽烟吗?
Look what some Johnny sent me.
看看强尼送给我的东西
Triple cream caramel, all the way from San Francisco.
从旧金山买来的三排装牛奶糖
l'm watching my figure. You know, the trial.
我在看我的案子,你是知道的,开庭的事
Hey, Great mentioned that you're on a trip today, huh?
嘿,听说你今天安排了行程,对吧?
There have been so many, l just can't keep track.
条文太多了,我简直记不了
Hey did I ever tell you, you're exactly the same size as my sister.
嘿,我可有告诉过你 你长的跟我妹妹同样大小?
l mean, you fit into her costume perfectly.
我是说你穿她的衣服刚好合身
Really?
真的?
Yeah, l was just thinking, you know,
对,我只是在想,你知道的
with all the publicity that's piled up between us when Billy gets us off,
既然这些媒体广告一直报导 比利帮我们俩个打官司的事
would we be a natural to do an act together.
我们一块表演应该会很棒
You think so huh?
你这么认为?
Ladies and gentlemen, Miss Velma Kelly in an act of desperation.
先生女士们,薇玛凯莉小姐卖命演出
My sister and l had an act that couldn't flop.
我妹妹和我跳些高难度动作
were headed straight for the top.
我妹妹和我直步青云
My sister and l earned a thou a week at least.
我妹妹和我一周至少赚进上千元
Oh yeah
是真的
But my sister is now unfortunately deceased.
但如今我妹已不幸离开人间
l know it's sad of course, but a fact is still a fact.
我深知是个悲惨的结果 但事实终究是事实
And now all that remains is the remains...
如今剩下的...依然是
of a perfect...
绝佳的...
double... act.
双人组...表演
Watch this.
看这个
They have to imagine it with 2 people. lt's swell with two people.
必须想像有两个人,两人才够棒
First, l'd...
首先,我...
Then,  she'd...
然後,她...
Then, we'd...
接著,我们...
But l can't do it alone.
但我一个人不行
Then, she'd...
然後,她...
Then, l'd...
然後,我...
Then, we'd...
接著,我们...
But l can't do it alone.
但我一个人不行
She'd say, what's your sister like?
她说,你妹妹长怎样?
l'd say, man.
我说,老兄啊
She'd say, you're the cat's meow And we wow the crowd again.
她就说,你真是棒极了 我们继续表演给群众看
When she'd go...
当她这样...
l'd go...
我就这样...
We'd go...
我们这样...
And then those ding-dong daddies started to roar Whistled, stomped, and stamped on the floor
然後那些花钱大爷开始叫嚣 吹口哨、跺著地板
Yelling, screaming, begging for more
嘶喊、尖叫著再多表演些
And we'd say, okay, fellows. Keep your socks up.
我们就说,好吧,各位,注意看好了
Cause you ain't seen nothing yet.
因为你还没看到真正的表演呢
But I simply cannot do it alone.
可是只有我一人无法表演
So what do you think?
那你觉得呢?
Come on, you can say.
快点,快说啦
l know you're right. The first part is shit.
我知道你说的对,第一段的确糟透了
But the second part...
但第二段...
Second part is really nifty.
第二段是真的很棒
Okay, she'd go...
好的,她这样...
l'd go...
我就这样...
We'd go...
我们就这样...
And then those two-bit Johnnies did it up brow
然後那些花钱大爷们个个瞠目结舌
To cheer the best attraction in town
为城里最棒的表演不停鼓掌
They really tore the balcony down
他们真的拆了看台
We'd say, okay, boys, we're going home.
我们说,好了,各位,我们要回家了
But before we go, here's a few more partin' shots!
但我们走之前,先开个几枪!
And this...this we did in perfect unison.
这段...这段我们一起做完美合唱
Now you've seen me going through it.
现在你看了我这样表演
You may think there's nothing to it.
你或许认为不怎么样
But l simply cannot do it...
但我只不过是无法...
Alone!
独自表演!
So where's the part we blew the brains out?
怎么没有开枪打的脑袋开花那段?
Okay, Roxie. l'll...
好的,萝西,我会...
No, don't bother.
不用了
You think you're fooling me? You're all washed up.
你以为你能耍的了我吗? 你已经过气了
And it's me they want now, and l'm a big star.
他们现在要的是我,我是个超级巨星
Single.
单人表演
Oh l almost forgot. You're in the paper today too.
哦,我差点忘了,你今天也上报了
ln the back.
在尾版
Velma Kelly's trial has been postponed indefinitely.
薇玛凯莉的审判已不知延到何年何月
Seven words.
才七个字
And here's a little piece of advice. Direct from me to you.
诚心给你一点小小的建议
Lay off the caramels.
少吃点牛奶糖
And now, for all you Chicago's stay-up-laters.
现在,为了全芝加哥的夜猫族
Night hours would only come alive at the dark.
夜生活只有在黑夜之下拉开序幕
We dedicate this tune Chicago After Midnight.
献上这曲"芝加哥午夜时分"
This all took place in Lesurevelt?
这全发生於雷瑟维特
lncredible.
太棒了
All right. Thanks.
好了,谢谢
They just arrest this woman for triple homicide.
警方刚逮捕了一名连杀三人的女人
Really?
真的?
Yeah, get this. She's an Aries!
对,听好了,她是白羊座的!
Now her family is in the pineapple or grapefruit, some kind of fruits.
她家是种△梨或葡萄的,种水果的就是了
The demon Kitty works in something... She's playing house.
这名穷凶恶极的凯蒂从事...戏院工作
On the north side in an apartment, she met Harry.
在一处公寓北边她碰见了哈利
What Harry does for living, no one's quite sure.
没人知道哈利是从事何种工作
But it doesn't really matter cause she's paying all the bills.
但那不重要,因为她也只是玩玩
Anyhow, Kitty comes home tonight. Harry was already in bed, which is a part of his course from Harry
总之,凯蒂今晚回到家 哈利已经在床上等了,哈利想的就是那个
She goes to change. When she returns, she notices something rather odd.
她去换衣服,等她回来後,发觉事有蹊跷
Extremely odd
真的很奇怪
Kitty disappears for a second.
凯蒂马上离开一下下
Cool as a cucumber
面无表情
And she returns, she gently wakes up Harry.
她回来之後,轻轻地唤醒哈利
Harry says, ''What? l'm alone!''
哈利说「怎么了? 我一个人呀!」
She says, ''Alone? Yyou have two other women in bed with you!''
她说「一个人? 床上还陪著两个女人!」
And Harry says, ''Come on, darling, you gonna believe what you see or what l tell you?''
哈利就说「拜托,亲爱的! 你一定得相信你看到或者我说的话」
Good night, folks.
晚安了,各位
Miss Baxter, Miss Baxter!
巴斯特小姐,巴斯特小姐!
Mary Sunshine from The Evening Star.
我是晨星日报的玛莉珊珊
Would you mind saying a word or two?
请你发表一两句好吗?
Sure l'll say three. Go to hell!
当然可以,我说那三个人下地狱去吧!
Please direct your questions to the counsel.
有话请留著对辩护律师说
You're not my counsel l want my money back!
你又不是我的辩护律师! 我要讨回我的钱
lt's not your money. lt's your mother's money.
那不是你的钱,是你妈的钱
Are you sorry, dear?
你後悔吗,亲爱的?
Yeah, l'm sorry, sorry l got caught.
是的,我很後悔...後悔被逮了
Oh hey, Miss Sunshine. Not now, Roxie.
嘿,珊珊小姐 现在不行,萝西
l got a letter from a guy. He says he's gone on a hungry strike until l'm free.
我收到一个家伙的来信 他说他要绝食抗议,直到我获释为止
That's nice.
那样很好啊
Miss Baxter, did you know these two ladies personally?
巴斯特小姐,你私底下认识那两名小姐吗?
Did l know these two ladies personally? Was that your question?
我私底下认识这两名小姐吗? 你是这么问吗?
Yeah, that's my ques...
对,那是我的问...
She's very hot spirit, isn't she?
她脾气可真暴躁,是不是呀?
Miss Baxter...
巴斯特小姐...
Oh hey, Mr. Flynn.
嘿,弗林先生
-Yeah, hi, Tracy. -lt's Roxie.
嗨,崔西 我是萝西
Yeah, sure, l'm just kidding.
是,没错,我只是开玩笑的
Did you get my trial date yet?
你知道我的开庭日是何时吗?
-Listen, kid. -l'm on top of your list, right?
听著 我还在你名单第一位是不是?
Go to hell!
去死吧!
What a helling, huh? And social-like too.
骚动可真不小,是吧? 社会大众也是
Her mother owns all the pineapples in Hawaii.
她母亲拥有夏威夷所有的△梨园
What the hell do l care about pineapples?
我才不管什么△不△梨的
All right...
好了,好了...
And now, that's all, direct all your questions
好了,到此为止,别再问了
And afterwards l'll be happy to get back to you myself.
稍後我会很乐意亲自替各位回覆
Billy...
比利...
How does it feel, kid?
滋味如何?
Pretty soon we couldn't find your name in the papers.
报纸上很快就看不到你的名字了
Mr. Flynn?
弗林先生?
Someone open this door immediately.
快点打开这扇门
Oh, my God. Roxie! What is it to you?
哦,天啊,萝西! 你怎么了?
Oh, no. Don't worry about me.
哦,不,我没事
l only hope the fall didn't hurt the baby.
但愿摔这一下没伤著了孩子
Baby?
孩子?
Shit!
他妈的!
Roxie, when did this happen darling?
萝西,你是何时发觉的,亲爱的?
Well, doctor, is she or isn't she?
医生,她到底有没有怀孕?
She is.
有的
Would you swear that statement in court?
你愿意出庭作证吗?
-Yes. -Good. Button your fly.
愿意 很好,你裤子拉链没关
I would...
我...
I would just like to say that when my own life doesn't matter now.
我只想说此刻我的生命已不重要了
just that of my unborn child.
重要的是我那未出世的孩子
Poor dear, to have your baby born in jail.
真可怜,竟然得在牢里生孩子
My readers won't stand for that.
我的读者们绝对无法忍受的
l can assure you that won't happen.
我可以向你保证绝不会那样的
The trial would come in the least possible moment.
一定会尽快开庭的
First time we're ever have one more girl knocked up.
我们这里还是头一遭平白多了个人呢
Hey, Roxie...
嘿,萝西...
Roxie! l just have the good news!
萝西! 我刚得到好消息!
l'm the father.
我是孩子的父亲
Hey, Roxie, who's the father?
嘿,萝西,谁是孩子的父亲?
The question is completely out of line.
这问题简直太无礼了
How dare you insult this brave young woman?
你怎能如此大胆地侮辱这位勇敢少妇?
That's enough
够了
Roxie, honey! lt's me, it's daddy!
萝西,亲爱的! 是我,我是孩子父亲!
Roxie, l'd get to you as soon as l could.
萝西,我会尽快救你出来的
If someone stood up in a crowd
如果有人站在群众当中
And raised his voice up way out loud
拉高了嗓子大声喊著
And waved his arm and shook his leg
挥动著双手,抖动著双腿
You'd notice him
你才会注意到他
If someone in the movie show Yelled "Fire in the second row
如果有人在电影院里喊著 「第二排失火了!」
This whole place is a powder keg!"
整个地方陷入一片火海
You'd notice him
你才会注意到他
And even without clucking like a hen
即使不像母鸡般咯咯叫
Everyone gets noticed, now and then
每个人多少会注意到
Unless, of course, that personage should be
当然啦,除非那些大人物通通...
Invisible, inconsequential me!
不见了...才会注意到微不足道的我!
Cellophane Mister Cellophane
玻璃纸,玻璃纸先生
Shoulda been my name
应该那么称呼我才对
'Cause you can look right through me
因为你能看穿我
Walk right by me
走过我身边
And never know I'm there...
却未能察觉我的存在...
I tell ya Cellophane Mister Cellophane
告诉你,玻璃纸,玻璃纸先生
Shoulda been my name
应该那么称呼我才对
'Cause you can look right through me
因为你能看穿我
Walk right by me
走过我身边
And never know I'm there
却未能察觉我的存在
Oh, l didn't see you. Sit down.
哦,我没看到你 坐下吧
Look, Andy, l'm afraid l'm gotta hit you hard.
听著,安迪,恐怕我会教你蒙受打击
l can only hope you would think about it.
只希望你能好好想一想
-Amos, my name is Amos. -Who says it wasn't?
艾默斯,我叫艾默斯 谁说不是来著?
lt was the kid's name l was thinking about.
我刚在想的是孩子的名字
You know when she's due? September.
你知道她何时分娩吗? 九月
You'd pass out those cigars anyway.
总之别理那些有的没的了
l don't want you to give a damn on the people. -People what?
我不想教你咒骂人们 人们怎么了?
-Laugh. -Laugh? Why would they laugh?
嘲笑 嘲笑? 他们干嘛嘲笑?
They can count. Can you count?
他们会算时间,你会算吗?
September.
九月
lt's the copy of Roxie's first statement from D.A. office.
这是D.A.办公室传来的萝西最初口供复本
Says she hasn't copulated with you for four months prior to the incidents.
上头写说她在命案发生前 跟你已经四个月没发生过性关系了
She would know. Yeah, l guess we've done no copulating since...
她会知道的 是的,我猜我们没行房是从...
Wait a minute.
等一下
That doesn't figure out right. l couldn't be the father.
那就不对了,我不可能是孩子父亲啊
Well, forget about that now My client needs your support.
嗯,先别管那个了 我的当事人　要你的支持
You mean she needs a meal ticket?
你意思是她　要个长期饭票吧?
That's all l've ever been. But this time she's gone too far.
我一直如此,不过这回她太过份了
What're you gonna do? Divorce her?
你怎么办? 跟她离婚吗?
You're damn right! l'll divorce her!
你说对了! 我要跟她离婚!
She probably won't even notice.
她可能根本不在乎
Yeah. l'm sorry.
我是,抱歉
A human being's made of more than air
一个比空气多些的人
With all that bulk, you're bound to see him there
要聚集很多,你才能看的见
Unless that human bein' next to you
若非在你旁边的那个人
Is unimpressive, undistinguished
让人印象不够深刻、默默无闻
You know who
你才会...知道...他是谁
-You're still here? -Yeah, l'm still here.
你还没走? 是的,我还在
I think
我认为
Shoulda been my name
我应该叫做...
Mister Cellophane
玻璃纸先生
'Cause you can look right through me
因为你能看穿我
Walk right by me
走过我身边
And never know I'm there
却未能察觉我的存在
Shoulda been my name
应该那么称呼我才对
'Cause you can look right through me
因为你能看穿我
Walk right by me
走过我身边
And never know I'm there
却未能察觉我的存在
Never even know
根本未能察觉...
I'm there
我的存在
Hope l didn't take up too much of your time.
希望没耽误你太多时间
l've been waiting for you 10 minutes. Don't do that again.
我等了你十分钟,下次不可再那样子
This dress makes me look like a wulworth lampshade. l'm not wearing this.
这件衣服穿起来像灯罩似的 我不要穿这件
You wear it because l tell you to wear it.
我叫你穿,你就得穿
l'm not wearing this dress.
我才不穿这件衣服呢
And when Andy's on the stand, l want you be knitting.
当安迪站在席上时,我要你编织著衣服
Knitting? For Christ's sake.
编织? 饶了我吧
-A baby garment. -l don't know how to knit!
婴儿衣服 我又不懂怎么编织!
Then learn. -That's no way to win the jury's sympathy.
那就学啊! 不可能博取陪审团同情的
-You don't need advice anymore? -Look at here, Mr. Mouthpiece.
你不用再　要建议了吗? 看看这篇,发言人先生
lt seems to me that l am the one who's coming up with the good ideas.
好像多亏我才想到这些好主意
l'm sick of everybody telling me what to do. And you treat me like dirt.
我厌烦了大家告诉我怎么做 而你又待我如同粪土
You know that? You treat me like I'm some dumb, common criminal.
你明白吗? 你待我有如某个又蠢又平凡的犯人
But you're some dumb,
但你的确是又蠢又平凡的犯人啊
Well, it's better than being a greasy mick lawyer.
总比当个滑头的爱尔兰律师来的好
-We're happy who's saving your ass. -Who's out for all. He can steal!
我们可是来救你的! 为了钱,当然肯出面!
Maybe you'd like to appeal on court without me.
也许你用不著我帮你出庭
Maybe l could. Have you read the morning papers? They love me.
也许我会,你看过今天早报了吗? 民众爱我
There maybe a lot more when you're hanged. You know why? 'Cause it's sold more papers.
才怪! 等你被吊死的时候会报更大篇 知道为什么吗? 因为报纸销售量会更好
-You're fired. -l quit.
你被解雇了 是我辞职了
Any lawyer in this town would die to have my case.
城里每个律师巴不得接我的案子
You're a phony celebrity. You're a flash in the pan
你是个虚假的名人 你只是昙花一现
ln a couple of weeks, no one would give a shit about you.
过没几个礼拜,就没人会理你了
That's Chicago.
那就是芝加哥
No! Not guilty!
不! 我没有罪!
What happened?
怎么回事?
lt's Hunyak. She lost the last appeal.
是韩雅,她最後一次上诉输了
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思?
What that means? Next week, she's gonna...
就是说...下周...她会...
This is Mary Sunshine, coming to you from the Cook County Jail,
我是玛莉珊珊,於库克郡立监狱为您报导
where history will be made today.
今天将创下历史纪录
Katelin Helinsky would become the first woman in the state of lllinois to be executed.
凯特琳海林斯基会成为伊利诺州 头一位被执行处决的女人
And so ladies and gentlemen...
所以先生女士们...
And now, ladies and gentlemen, for your pleasure and your entertainment,
现在,先生女士们,请尽兴观赏底下节目
we proudly present Katelin Helinsky and her famous Hungarian Disappearing Act.
很荣幸请到凯特琳海林斯基 和她名闻遐迩的匈牙利消失表演
Bravo!
太棒了!
You know, it's really not that bad.
你知道吗? 其实也没那么难看啦
You're clear with everything we agreed on?
我们套好的通通记清楚了吗?
Yup. l've been up all night rehearsing.
好了,我背了一整晚
What do you do when Harrison comes after you?
当哈里森走向你时,你要怎么做?
l sit still and look straight ahead. Never look the jury.
我乖乖坐著,眼睛看著前面 别看陪审团
-And? -And l look modest.
还有呢? 我要表现得很文静
-And...
还有...
-And say nothing. -That's right, that's right.
一句话也不说 没错,没错
-That was the deal, right? -Right.
那这么说定了,对吧? 对
You ask me back, l do all the talking and stuff.
你若顶嘴,我就把事情通通抖出来
Absolutely, Billy. Whatever you say.
不管你说怎样,我绝对配合,比利
-Mr. Flynn, his honor is here. -Thank you.
弗林先生,法官大人到了 谢谢
You ready?
准备好没?
Yeah.
好了
Billy...
比利...
l'm scared.
我好害怕
Na, don't be.
别害怕
l've been around a long time. Believe me, you've got nothing to worry about.
我干这行很久了 相信我,你一点也不用担心
lt's all a circus. A three-ring circus.
法庭就像马戏团,场面闹哄哄的而已
These trials, the whole world... it's all the show business.
这些审判,全世界...都是演戏罢了
But kid
不过孩子...
You're working with a star
和你搭档演出的可是个演技派巨星呢!
Give 'em the old razzle dazzle
给他们老噱头
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
Give 'em act with lots of flash in it
给他们目不暇给的演出
And the reaction will be passionate
他们会报以热情掌声
Give 'em the old hocus pocus
给他们老把戏
Bead and feather 'em
珠珠、羽毛
How can they see with sequins in their eyes?
满眼尽是金光闪闪
What if your hinges all are rusting?
万一你的链子全生　了呢?
What if, in fact, you're just disgusting?
万一那样,事实上,就太　心了
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
And they'll never catch wise
他们便会真假不分
Give 'em the old razzle dazzle
给他们老噱头
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
Give 'em a show that's so splendiferous
给他们场面豪华的秀
Row after row will grow vociferous
一场接一场,更加欢声雷动
Give 'em the old flim flam flummox
给他们老戏法
Fool and fracture 'em
愚弄他们
How can they hear the truth above the roar?
这么吵他们如何听得清真相呢?
Throw 'em a fake and a finagle
制造假象欺骗他们
They'll never know you're just a bagel
他们绝不会知道你只是个甜甜圈
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
And they'll beg you for more
他们会求你多表演些
-Object! -Sustained.
抗议! 抗议准许
Your honour, l haven't even asked a question yet.
庭上,我连问都还没问呢!
Give 'em the old double whammy
给他们双重打击
Daze and dizzy 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
Back since the days of old Methuselah
回复到以前麦修撒拉时代
Everyone loves the big bambooz-a-ler
人人喜欢冤大头
Give 'em the old three ring circus
给他们热闹场面
Stun and stagger 'em
让他们目瞪口呆
When you're in trouble, go into your dance
当你麻烦缠身,就尽情跳舞吧
Though you are stiffer than a girder
就算你再坚毅不拔
They let ya get away with a murder
他们也会让你摆脱谋杀罪名
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
And you've got a romance
你已浪漫过一回
Hello, Amos.
你好,艾默斯
Amos? That's right, Mr. Flynn. Amos
艾默斯? 没错,弗林先生. 艾默斯
Amos, when did you file sue for divorce?
艾默斯,你何时提出诉请离婚?
A month ago.
一个月前
Was there any reason for filing at this particular time?
有何理由非得在此特别时刻提出来吗?
l'd say, the newspapers said Roxie was expecting a little stranger.
我说,报纸上说萝西怀了个小杂种
That's hardly a cause for divorce, isn't it?
那根本不足以构成离婚,不是吗?
A little too much of a stranger.
一个超级小杂种
You mean you doubted the fraternity of the child.
我想你意思是,你怀疑孩子的血缘
Well sure.
一点也没错
Tell me something, Amos. You share a bed with your wife?
回答我,艾默斯 你跟你老婆同床睡觉吗?
Yes, sir, every night.
是的,先生,每晚都睡在一块
You expect the jury to believe that
你认为陪审团会相信...
you slept next to this woman every night without exercising the rights of a husband?
你每晚和这名女人睡觉 却未履行丈夫应尽的义务吗?
-l could if l want to. -Oh, but you didn't.
我想干随时能干 哦,可是你并没有
-No, l did. -Did what?
不,我有干 干什么?
-Want to. -But you didn't.
我想干的事 但你没有干
-Didn't what? -What you wanted.
没干什么? 你想干的事
Wait a minute, l'm getting confused here.
等等,我有点搞迷糊了
Hey, you tell me, Hart. Since you ever question Roxie herself,
嘿,老实告诉我,哈特 从你怀疑萝西开始
did you even bother to ask her if you were the father of the child?
你可有问过她你是不是孩子的父亲?
-No, sir. -No. What?
没有,先生 没有? 什么?
lf you became convinced that you were wrong, you'd be mad enough in a minute.
要是你开始认为你搞错了的话 包准你会马上疯掉
You would take her back if Roxie swore that you're the father of the child,
如果萝西发誓说你就是孩子的父亲 你才愿意带她回去
-which she does. -She does?
她发誓了 真的?
She does!
真的!
No more question! You can step down now.
我没问题了! 你可以退席了
Well done, Andy.
干的好,安迪
Roxie, l'm so sorry.
萝西,我真的很抱歉
Give 'em the old razzle dazzle
给他们老噱头
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
Show 'em the first rate sorcerer you are
给他们看你是一等一的魔法师
Long as you keep 'em way off balance
只要你教他们保持平衡
How can they spot you got no talents?
又怎会发现你是个大草包?
Razzle dazzle 'em
让他们眼花撩乱
This is the moment we've been waiting for.
我们一直等待的时刻来临了
Roxie Hart finally takes the stand in her own defense.
萝西哈特终於就自己辩护位置
And they'll make you a star!
他们会把你捧为耀眼明星!
Hold it!
安静!
Proceed, Mr. Flynn.
可以开始了,弗林先生
Roxie, l have here a statement which you admitted having illicit relations
萝西,我这里有份你承认有婚外情的口供
with deceased Fred Casely. ls this statement true or false?
对象是死去的佛瑞德凯斯利 这份口供是真是假?
l'm afraid that's true.
恐怕那是真的
You're an honestly girl, Roxie.
你很诚实,萝西
When did you first meet Fred Casely?
你第一次遇见佛瑞德凯斯利是何时?
When he sold Amos and me our furniture.
在他卖家俱给艾默斯和我的时候
Your personal relationship with him, you tell the jury when that began.
跟他何时发生亲密关系呢? 请告诉陪审团何时开始的
When l permitted him to escort me home one night,
有一晚我答应让他护送我回家
l don't think l would've gone with him
要不是那天早上哈特先生和我发生了口角
if Mr. Hart and me hadn't quarreled that very morning.
我也不会跟他一块走
-Quarreled? -Yes, sir.
口角? 是的,先生
Well, l supposed it was his fault.
嗯,我猜那是他的错罗
Oh, no, sir. lt was my fault.
哦,不,先生,是我的错
l supposed l just couldn't stop pestering him.
我猜想是我一直烦他的缘故
Pestering him? About what?
烦他? 关於什么事?
l didn't like him working those long hours at the garage.
我不喜欢他在修车厂工作时间那么长
l wanted him home with me... to darn his socks and iron his shirts.
我想要他在家陪我... 帮他缝补袜子、烫平衬衫
l wanted a real home and a child.
我想要一个真正的家和孩子
So you drifted into this illicit relationship because you're unhappy at home.
所以你是因为在家不美满 才导致这段婚外情
Yes, was almost unhappy.
是的,几近不美满
Roxie Hart!
萝西哈特!
The state has accused you the murder of Fred Casely.
本州控告你谋杀了佛瑞德凯斯利
Are you guilty or not guilty?
你认不认罪?
l'm not guilty...
我没有罪...
I'm not guilty
我没有罪
l killed him, l did. But l'm not a criminal. l'm not a criminal...
我是杀了他没错,不过我不是罪犯 我不是罪犯...
Roxie...
萝西...
Do you recall the night of June 14th?
你可还记得6月14日那晚的事?
Could you tell the jury in your own words the happenings of that night.
请你亲口告诉陪审团当晚发生情形好吗?
Well when Fred came over, l told him a good news.
当佛瑞德过来时,我告诉他一个好消息
What was it?
什么好消息?
That me and Amos are gonna have a baby. And it was all over between us.
我和艾默斯快有小孩了 我们之间的关系已经结束了
What happened then?
後来发生什么事呢?
Then...
後来...
Did he threaten you, Roxie?
他威胁你是不是,萝西?
Objection, your honour. Counsel is leading the witness.
抗议,庭上! 辩护律师在引导证人
Sustained.
抗议准许
What did Casely say when you told him the news?
当你告诉他这消息时,凯斯利怎么回答?
l'll kill you before l see you have another man's child!
你敢生别的男人的孩子,我就宰了你!
Could you tell the audience... the jury, what happened next?
可否告诉观众...陪审团,接下来怎么了?
ln his passion, he tore off my robe and he threw me on the bed.
他很激动,撕开我的睡袍 把我甩到床上
And Mr. Hart's pistol was lying there between us.
哈特先生的手枪刚好放在我俩中间
And then!
然後呢?
And then we both reached for the gun but l got it first.
然後我俩同时去抢那把枪,但我抢先一步
And then he came towards me with this awny look in his eyes.
接著他用他那恶狠狠的眼光扑向我
He was angry and wild!
他气得快抓狂了!
Wild!
抓狂了!
And did you think that he might kill you?
你是不是以为他想杀了你?
Oh, yes, sir!
哦,是的,先生!
So was his life or yours?
那不是他死就是你亡罗?
And l just mine. l closed my eyes and l shot!
我只是想保住自己性命 我闭上眼睛开了一枪!
It is defense for your life!
这是自卫杀人!
To save my husband's innocent unborn child.
为了拯救我老公无辜的未出世小孩
Order!
安静!
What a bull's eye, huh?
正中下怀了,是吧?
-Order in this courtroom! -Roxie!
法庭内请维持秩序! 萝西!
It's come demonian here in the courtroom...
现在法庭内一片混乱...
Mrs. Hart's behavior has been truly extraordinary.
哈特先生的举动真的教人钦佩
Opening her eyes, she fenced herself with her attorney's handkerchief.
她一张开眼睛,就用律师的手帕挡著
-Handkerchief? -Poor child has no relief.
手帕? 可怜的孩子无处宣泄
She looks around now bewildered, seeming to want something.
她现在惊慌失措地环顾四周 像在找什么东西似的
lt's a glass of water.
喝了杯水
Oh, Mama, that was my bid! l told Billy, l'm gonna do that at my trial!
哦,妈妈,那是我的台词! 我告诉过比利,我开庭时会那样子做!
But now her eyes flatter wildly and she...
但此刻她不断眨著眼睛,然後她...
Mrs. Hart has fainted again.
哈特太太又昏过去了
She flumps over her chiffon dress up around her knees,
她倒在地上,丝质洋装盖住了膝盖
revealing a glimpse of blue garter with Ryan-stone buckle.
稍微露出了一点有著莱恩史东扣环的 蓝色吊带袜
Oh, Mama, she stole my garter. She stole my garter!
哦,妈妈,她偷穿我的吊带袜 她偷穿我的吊带袜!
Don't break my radio!
别砸了我的收音机!
First the slut steals my publicity, then she steals my lawyer, my trial date,
这贱女人先是偷了我的知名度 接著偷了我的律师、我的开庭日
now she stole my goddamn garter.
现在又偷了我他妈的吊带袜
What do you expect?
不然你想怎样?
l mean these days you get a little success
我是说这些日子你也获得少许成功
and it's good rinse for the people who put you here.
对那些捧红你的人也有好处
lt ain't no justice in the world. That's nothing you can do about it.
世上没有所谓的正义,你根本无能为力
Notes that
话是没错
You think they got you a page just to listen to my radio?
你以为他们把你关进来 只是来听我收音机吗?
People write some public interesting things when they think no one's looking.
他们认为没人想看时 就会写些大众感兴趣的东西
Oh, Mama.
哦,妈妈
State calls a witness.
传唤证人
Left hand on the Bible, raise your right hand and swear you'd tell the truth, the whole truth, nothing but truth swear to God.
左手放在圣经上,举起右手 对天发誓所讲的话句句属实
Have a seat.
请坐下
Would you state your name for the record please.
请说一下你的名字以便纪录下来
Velma Kelly.
薇玛凯莉
Miss Kelly, would you please tell the court of the object l'm holding
凯莉小姐,请你告诉庭上我现在手上拿的
is the one you happen to come upon in the defendant jailhouse?
和你在被告牢房里不小心看到的 是同一本吗?
Yes, it is.
是的,同一本
l submit this as Exhibitdex. Roxie Hart's diary.
我想将此列为证物,萝西哈特的日记
l object! My client never kept a diary.
抗议! 我的当事人根本没写日记
Even if she did, this would be invasion of privacy and violation of fourth amendment
就算有,这也是侵犯了个人隐私权 以及触犯宪法第四条修正法案
and illegal search without a warrant.
未持搜索票进行非法搜索
Yeah, and she broke the law.
对,她触犯了法律
Order!
安静!
Well, let's settle that. l'll allow it.
好了,我们来解决一下,我批准
What's the big deal? She's the one that did it.
有什么大不了的? 她真的犯了法呀
lf you would read for us, Miss Kelly.
请为我们念一下好吗,凯莉小姐?
l haven't worked in a while.
我喘口气马上开始念
What a laugh, plucking Fred Casely.
除掉了佛瑞德凯斯利,真是大快人心!
The big baboon had a common.
这支大狒狒的小弟弟没多大根
l'm just sorry l only got to kill him once.
我只是很遗憾只能杀他一回
l never wrote that. You... Hey, she made that up.
我没写过那个,你... 嘿,是你! 是她捏造出来的!
-She made that up! -Order!
是她捏造的! 安静!
Please, Mr. Flynn, get control of your client.
弗林先生,请克制一下你的当事人
l'm sorry, you honour. lt won't happen again.
抱歉,庭上,不会再那样了
Sit down and shut up. Or else it gonna get worse.
坐下来闭上嘴巴,否则事情会变糟的
l have no more questions.
我没有问题了
Your witness, Mr. Flynn.
换你发问,弗林先生
Ladies and gentlemen, a tap dance.
先生女士们,踢踏舞
Tell me, Miss Kelly, you make a deal with Mr. Harrison
告诉我,凯莉小姐 你是否跟哈里森先生达成协议?
maybe to drop all charges against you in exchange of your testifying today?
也许是说只要你今天出庭作证 便撤销对你所有的指控
No, sure. l'm not completed yet.
当然没有,还没达成协议呢!
Good.
很好
Then since you gave such an impressive performance for Mr. Harrison,
既然你替哈里森先生做出 如此印象深刻的演出
can you do me the same honour?
能同样帮我念一段吗?
-l'd be delighted. -Thank you.
乐意之至 谢谢
Fred Casely assured me to get me an audition down at the Onyx.
佛瑞德凯斯利向我保证帮我争取到 在玛瑙试镜的机会
And then he reneged on his pledge and that was my motive for attack.
之後却食言而肥 那便是我采取攻击的动机
Pretty fancy. What you're saying
讲的相当好,你讲的是...
if a big fat liar who rogue on a deal so l shot him.
他是一个违反誓言的超级大骗子 所以我才对他开枪
Amos accused me of having an affair.
艾默斯指控我有外遇
So l told him that the charge was erroneous.
所以我告诉他那是不对的
Objection, your honour.
抗议,庭上!
Mr. Flynn is twisting the evidence to draw conclusion to the specious and the...
弗林先生歪曲证据,好让结论似是而非 而且...
-Erroneous? -Exactly.
似是而非? 没错
Order!
安静!
Miss Kelly, did you know the meaning of the word perjury?
凯莉小姐,你可知道什么是作伪证吗?
Yes, l do.
是的,我知道
-You also know that is a crime? -Yes.
你是否也知道那是犯法的吗? 知道
And for example if it turns out you knew this diary was a fake,
譬如说,万一你发现这本日记是假的呢?
l hate to think you rotting away in prison for the next 10 years
我可不想教你往後十年在牢里憔悴不堪
especially when you just win your freedom.
尤其是你才刚获得自由不久
All l know is what l was told.
我只是把我所知道的讲出来而已
So... you didn't find this diary in Roxie's cell?
所以... 你并没有在萝西的牢房里找到这本日记?
No.
没有
Mama... Miss Morton gave it to me. She said someone sent it to her.
是妈妈...摩顿小姐交给我的 她说是有人寄给她的
Someone? Any idea who this mysterious benefactor might be?
有人寄的? 知道可能是哪位神秘客寄的吗?
No. She didn't know.
不,她不清楚
All right, let's see if it's gonna work so
好了,我们来看看这样行不行的通
Someone who writes about reneging on pledges.
有人写了这些背信的事
And... erroneous charges...
并做出了...错误的指控...
Call me crazy, does that sound like a lawyer to you?
若我没疯的话 这听起来是不是像律师写的?
A lawyer, who honestly had a sample of my client's handwriting.
一位律师,能拿得到我当事人笔迹样本
Mr. Harrison, did you ask Roxie to write out a confession for you?
哈里森先生,你有叫萝西写供词给你吗?
Yes, but you're not suggesting that l tempered with evidence, are you?
有的,但你不会是在质疑我捏造证据吧?
No, let's not be ridiculous.
不,别让人笑掉大牙了
That's certainly and utterly absurd.
那肯定太荒诞了
Unless you mention it.
除非你有提到
Your honour, this is outrageous.
庭上,这简直是血口喷人
Outrageous? Yes.
血口喷人? 没错
The prosecutor would made a thief bargain with notorious  Velma Kelly.
检察官竟和声名狼藉的薇玛凯莉 偷偷达成协议
And then fabricated the very evidence and set her free!
然後伪造这份证据好让她获释!
Mr. Flynn, hold your contempt.
弗林先生,别再藐视法庭
No, it's not even conceivable.
不,真令人想像不到
But does it worked? Would it be time to say,
但是有用吗? 是不是该承认了
Come clean, Mr. Harrison, come clean...
招供吧,哈里森先生,招供吧...
Even with your , this kind of corruption. l cannot stand.
你这样捣乱,我受不了了
That's enough, Mr. Flynn!
够了,弗林先生!
l agree, your honour. That's enough!
我同意,庭上,真是受够了!
Let defence rest
辩护暂停一下休息吧
Ladies and gentlemen,
先生女士们...
this is Mary Sunshine reporting live from the Cooke County Courthouse.
这里是玛莉珊珊从库克郡立监狱 所做的现场报导
The city of Chicago has come to a complete stand still.
芝加哥城一片鸦雀无声
As the trial of century finally draw to a close.
世纪审判终於接近了尾声
Mrs. Hart sits quietly at the defense table, hands folded.
哈特太太静静地端坐在被告席,双手张开
Wondering what fate has installed for her?
心想她日後命运不知将会如何?
And how hushing over the courtroom
整个法庭内静悄悄地
as the 12 men of the jury fall slowly back to their seats.
12位陪审团成员慢慢地返回他们的座位
Gentlemen of the jury, have you reach a verdict?
陪审团,可有达成一致决议?
We have, your honour.
有的,庭上
The jury has reached a verdict.
陪审团已达成一致决议
The defendant please rise.
被告请起立
What is your verdict?
决议为何?
We, the jury, find the defendant...
我们陪审团认为被告...
"Guilty"
"有罪"
"Innocent"
"无辜"
Roxie Hart is innocent! She's innocent!
萝西哈特无罪释放! 她是无辜的!
Get your paper
快来买报纸啊!
Roxie Hart is free!
萝西哈特自由了!
She's free
她自由了
Roxie
萝西
Come on! Move it!
快点! 走开!
She shoots her husband and she crossed the lawyer!
她射杀了她的老公,还勾搭上律师!
Hey, don't you wanna take my picture?
嘿,你们不想帮我拍照吗?
Hey, l'm the famous Roxie Hart.
嘿,我是那红透半边天的萝西哈特呀
Hey, what happened? What the hell happened?
嘿,怎么了? 到底发生什么事?
lt's Chicago, kid. You can't beat fresh blood on the walls.
这里是芝加哥呀,孩子,凡事都讲究新鲜
What about my publicity, Billy? My name in the papers.
那我的宣传呢,比利? 我的名字上报了呀
l was counting on that.
我全靠它了呀
Your attitude is not the one l get. l just save your life.
你不该对我这种态度,我刚救了你一命
You got $5,000. What do l get? l get nothing.
你赚了五千美元 而我得到什么? 一无所获
Five? Actually it's ten once l collect from Velma.
五千? 实№上是一万 薇玛那边再捞一票就有了
l get nothing?
我什么也得不到?
Don't forget your diary.
别忘了你的日记
If you don't mind. l had a few erroneous phrases in there.
不介意的话,我在里头发现不少语法错误
Sorry, l couldn't tell you.
抱歉,我无法告诉你了
Take a chance.
碰碰运气吧!
Never lost a case.
我还未败诉过
You're a free woman, Roxie Hart.
你自由了,萝西哈特
And God save lllinois.
愿上帝拯救伊利诺州
Roxie.
萝西
What do you want?
你想干嘛?
l want you to come home.
我要你一起回家
You said you still wanted to... and the baby...
你说过你仍然想...还有孩子呀...
Baby, what baby?
孩子,哪来的孩子?
Oh, Jesus.
哦,老天
What do you take me for?
不然你要我怎么办?
There ain't no baby.
根本没有孩子
There ain't no baby?
没有孩子?
They didn't even want my picture.
他们甚至不想替我拍照
l just can't understand that.
我简直无法理解那点
Why didn't they even want my picture?
他们为何连帮我拍个照都不想?
It's good, isn't it?
太好了,是不是?
Grand, isn't it?
好极了,是不是?
Great, isn't it?
太棒了,是不是?
Swell, isn't it?
棒极了,是不是?
Fun, isn't it?
是不是很有趣啊?
Nowadays
现在...
Ladies and gentlemen, Miss Roxie Hart says Good Night.
先生女士们,萝西哈特小姐道声晚安
There's man, everywhere
男人...比比皆是
Jazz, everywhere
爵士...比比皆是
Booze, everywhere
美酒...比比皆是
Life, everywhere
生命...比比皆是
Joy, everywhere
欢乐...比比皆是
Nowadays
现在...
You can like the life you're living
你可以满意目前过的生活
You can live the life you like
也可以追求你想要的生活
You can even marry Harry
甚至可以嫁给了哈利
But mess around with Ike
却跟艾克胡搞
And that's good, isn't it?
那样太好了,是不是?
Grand, isn't it?
好极了,是不是?
Great, isn't it?
太棒了,是不是?
Swell, isn't it?
棒极了,是不是?
Fun, isn't it?
是不是很有趣啊?
But nothing stays
但花无百日红
You can like the life you're living
你可以满意目前过的生活
You can live the life you like
也可以追求你想要的生活
Didn't she kill a guy a while back?
她之前不是杀了一个男的吗?
Yeah, who can keep it straight anymore?
对,谁还记的了那么多?
But mess around with Ike
却跟艾克胡搞
And that's good, isn't it?
那样太好了,是不是?
Grand, isn't it?
好极了,是不是?
Great, isn't it?
太棒了,是不是?
Swell, isn't it?
棒极了,是不是?
That's great. We'll be in touch.
太棒了,我们再跟你连络
You know l'm not quite finished yet. l have a...
你明知道我还没唱完,我有...
Wait, don't go.
等一下,别走
l could... just a second I'm not...
我可以...等一下,我不是...
Goddamn it!
可恶!
Thank you!
谢谢!
Here's your music, honey.
你的乐谱在这,甜心
Thanks.
谢了
You know you're really pretty good.
你知道你的确相当棒
Yeah.
是的
What are you doing here?
你来这里做什么?
l've been making around.
我一直在从事表演
Well, if not fooled up by you, l'll be swinging right now.
嗯,要不是被你捣乱,我现在也在表演了
Come on, l was there to get you off.
少来,我是来救你的
You should learn how to put things behind you.
你应该学会如何忘记一些事情
Thank you. l'll put that at the top of my list
哦,谢谢! 我会好好记住的
right after finding a job and an apartment with a john.
等我找到工作和一间含厕所的公寓再说
Can you shut up and listen to me?
你闭上嘴听我说好吗?
You really are something.
你真是大摇大摆
Coming in here like some goddamn queen bee, full of advice for a poor slob like me.
像个天杀的女王蜂似的跑进来 对我这样的穷光蛋满口忠告
Let me tell you something, Miss Velma Kelly.
我告诉你一件事,薇玛凯莉小姐
l got a new life now.
我现在过著新生活
And one of the best thing about it, is it don't include you.
其中最棒的就是,不用再看到你了
Fine. l just thought we could help each other out.
很好,我原本想说我们可以互相帮忙
Wait, you thought wrong, didn't you?
等等,你想错了,是不是?
Now look, listen to me.
现在听好,仔细听我说
Look l talked to this guy downtown.
听著,我跟市中心的人谈过
He says one chance hurts nothing these days, but two...
他说最近日子给一次机会是没问题 不过两次就...
We can make a couple hundred a week.
我们可以一周净赚数百元
Think about it, Roxie.
考虑一下吧,萝西
Our faces back in the papers our names in the market.
我们的脸孔再度上报 我们的名字传遍大街小巷
Velma Kelly and Roxie Hart.
薇玛凯莉和萝西哈特
Shouldn't it be alphabetical?
不是该照字母排名吗?
That could work.
那样也行
A couple hundred? Maybe we can ask for a thousand.
数百元? 也许我们可以要到一千元
We'll worth it.
绝对值得
Forget it, it'll never work.
算了,行不通的
-Why not? -'Cause l hate you.
为何不行? 因为我讨厌你
There's only one business in the world that's no problem at all.
这世界上只剩一种行业可做了
Ladies and gentlemen, the Chicago theatre is proud to announce the first.
先生女士们,芝加哥剧院很荣幸 第一间邀请到
The first time anywhere that's been an act out of this nation.
首度在国内演出的...
Not only one little lady, but two.
不只一位,而是两位
You read about them in the papers, and now here they are.
你们在报上听过她们的新闻 现在她们来了
Chicago zone killer-dealers, the lady-sinners,
芝加哥地区杀人贩,罪孽小姐
Roxie Hart and Velma Kelly!
萝西哈特与薇玛凯莉!
You can like the life you're living
你可以满意目前过的生活
You can live the life you like
也可以追求你想要的生活
You can even marry Harry
甚至可以嫁给了哈利
But mess around with Ike
却跟艾克胡搞
And that's good, isn't it?
那样太好了,是不是?
Grand, isn't it?
好极了,是不是?
Great, isn't it?
太棒了,是不是?
Swell, isn't it?
棒极了,是不是?
Fun, isn't it?
是不是很有趣啊?
But nothing stays
但花无百日红
In fifty years or so
经过五十年之後
It's gonna change, you know
人事全非,你知道的
But, oh, it's heaven
但是,哦,彷佛置身天堂
Nowadays
把握现在
Okay, you babes of Jazz, Let's pick up the pace.
好了,爵士辣妹,加快节奏吧!
Let's make the party longer, let's make the skirt shorter.
让舞会更久点,让裙子更短些
Let's all go to hell in a fast car and KEEP IT HOT
让我们全搭乘跑车直通地狱 热热闹闹一番
Me and Roxie would just like to say thank you.
我和萝西只想说:谢谢大家
Thank you!
谢谢!
Believe us, we could've never done anything without you!
相信我们,没有你们,我们也办不到!
And all that Jazz
纵情爵士
That Jazz
爵士风情!